Hi there. Welcome to Lesson 1,
this is Introduction to Data Modeling.
In this lesson, you will understand the strengths and weaknesses of
different types of relational databases and non-relational databases,
and the fundamentals of data modeling for both types of databases.
My name is Amanda Moran,
and I will be your instructor for this course.
Throughout these lessons, I'll be introducing you to
the concept of data modeling and how you can use
them to organize your data that can be easily queried and utilized by your organization.
So before we get started,
I just wanted to tell you a little bit about myself.
I'm a bachelor's in science in biology from
the University of Washington and a master's in
computer science and engineering from Santa Clara University.
I worked as a Software Engineer at HP, SGEN,
Luckheed Martin, and Teradata on three different distributed databases.
I'm an Apache committer and I'm on the project management committee
for a open source project called Apache travodia.
For data stacks, I'm a Developer Advocate.
Developer Advocate is a Software Engineer that's in the middle layer
between our internal engineering organization and our users,
our developers, and our customers