Okay. So let's get to my favorite thing which are demos.
So we're going to jump over here to Demo 0 because we're all computer scientists here.
Of course, we're going to start with zero instead of starting with one.
So let's create a table with PostgreSQL.
So here as you can see,
I have my jupyter notebook open.
I love interacting with jupyter and using that
because it's so nice to have a clean data here,
so it's really just my favorite thing to use.
So we're going to be focusing on using jupyter notebooks
and using Python wrappers to execute our queries.
All these queries are also able to do them just in either Postgres shell,
but we're just going to focus on utilizing a Python wrapper for these.
Actually I'm just going to talk about something that you may hit
when you're working with Postgres and it's about AutoCommits.
So Lesson 1 Demo 0: PostgreSQL and AutoCommits.
So in this case, we're going to use this Python package here.
Let's go ahead and run that.
We're going to use this as our wrapper this Python package to wrap around Postgres.
In my case I'm working off my own machine.
I seem to get an error here,
but actually it's properly installed,
then if I just run it again it works.
So if you're working on your own and you see an arrow like that,
read it carefully but it may just be something
actually it's just signifying that they're going to be changing the name soon.
So it's a nice warning but not really necessary.
So let's create a connection to our database.
This connects in my case to a local instance of Postgres.
From there we're going to use the database and
Schema which in this case is the student dB,
and then our username and password.
Remember this is just the demo,
so the password is in clear text but you would never do that in production.
This connection will reach out to the database and ensure
that we have the correct privileges to connect to the database.
Let's run that and it's successfully ran.
So next let's use the connection to get a cursor,
and we'll use that to execute the query.
We have our cursor now.
So lets try to actually run a query.
So let's start from test one, two, three.
No, we have an error.
Okay. It says relation tests one,
two, three does not exist.
Okay. That's no problem.
So we had an error, but we were expecting that.
So let's go fix this error by creating a table.
So I'm going to create table test one, two, three.
This is just an example,
I have three columns and they're all Ints.
I'm going to run this. I've gotten another error.
Current transaction is aborted,
command's ignored until end of transaction block.
That's not what I was expecting at all.
So when you're using Postgres,
what we need to make sure that we understand is that again because we're working with
an acid database that we need to make sure that we commit our transactions.
So when I had that error in
my query I did not commit my transaction and so I got an error.
So as we have not committed the transaction,
we had an error in our transaction block.
At this point we're blocked until we restart the connection,
or we could have committed the transaction either one.
So let's just re-get our connection.
Okay. So we're going to connect to our database,
and then we're going to get our cursor.
In these exercises the point of this demo is to instead of worrying about
committing after each transaction or getting that strange error that we just hit,
let's just set auto commit to true.
So this says that after each call during this session,
commit that one action and do not hold open the transaction for any other actions.
So one action will equal one transaction.
For this demo we're going to set autocommit in the session to true.
So this line here.
We won't have to call con.commit for each command,
and that executes successfully.
So let's try this again.
Let's do select star from test one, two, three.
Okay. We got an error,
that's what we expected.
Now let's go down here and let's try to create that table.
Let's solve our problem. Create table test one, two,
three with our three columns,
and execute it successfully.
Wonderful that's exactly what we wanted.
When we executed this code again with auto commit set to true,
we didn't face any issues with the transaction blocks,
and we did not need to restart our connection.
So let's just do a select star from test one, two, three,
and since we don't have anything there we didn't get
anything back, and let's do a select,
count star, and we see that we have
zero rows in the table because we didn't add anything.
Then let's just drop the table.
So this was just a demo to make sure that you understand why
we're setting autocommit in each one of our demos.