So from here, we're going to move on to Lesson 1,
Demo 1, and this is all about creating a table in Postgres.
So in this demo, we're going to walk through the basis of creating a table and Postgres.
Inserting rows of data and doing a simple SQL query to validate that information.
Like I said before, we're going to use a Python wrapper,
and you can find more information about it here.
If It's not installed on your local machine I've also included
the command that you could run to install it on your local machine,
but it should be installed in your workspace.
We're going to import the library, again,
if an error pops up make sure that you read it thoroughly,
but it may be something you can ignore.
All right, let's create a connection to the database.
This connects to our local instance in our case of Postgres,
from there we'll use the database and the schema.
This connection will reach up to the database and ensure that we
have the correct privileges to connect this database.
So I just want to let you know just here's
a note this block of code that you're seeing here,
is going to be very standard in all our notebooks.
We're adding this try-except block to make sure that errors are caught and understood.
This is just good coding techniques and practice.
So you need to have that just to make sure that you're catching any errors,
but you really want to focus on what's in the try command.
The rest is just pretty standard,
we'll be using it again and again.
So let's run this block of code we're going to make our connection,
and next we're going to use that connection to get a cursor,
so we can use that cursor to execute the queries,
and that we didn't know errors were thrown.
So again, for this demo we're going to use the auto commit for each action is
committed without having to call that conduct commit after each command.
The ability to roll back and commit transactions are a feature of relational databases.
So let's test our connection and our error handling.
Lets do a select star on a table that we have not yet created.
We should expect to see a nicely handled error.
So let's do a select star from udacity.music_library.
All right, good. We saw an error.
udacity.music_library does not exist.
Exactly. We haven't created it yet and we saw
an error where we were able to successfully connect to our database.
So let's actually create a database so that we can do our work.
So let's create the database Udacity.
So create database Udacity.
Wonderful. Well, in this case it already exists for me,
but when you run it you'll create it for the first time.
Let's close our connection to this default database,
that first connection that we made and
reconnect to the Udacity database and get a new cursor.
So as you can see here we're going to close the connection,
and then from there we're going to connect to our new database,
and then we're going to get the cursor.
So all those are going to happen in the same cell,
and we also set our auto commit to true and all of that ran successfully.
So now that we've done some of that upfront work,
let's actually start thinking about creating our table.
So let's imagine we're going to start creating a music library of albums.
Each album has a lot of information we could add to this music library table,
but we'll start with just the album name,
artist's name, and year.
The type of table we want to create and
the columns we need seemed to really fall out very naturally.
So let's imagine that our table name's going to be music library.
We're going to have three columns one called album name,
artist name, and year.
So now we want to translate this into a create table statement.
So if you want to review more documentation on Postgres and their data types,
you can find that information here in this link that I provided.
So again, in our try catch block,
we're going to create table if not exist.
So if it doesn't already exist create it,
if it does exist, don't create it.
We're going to call it Music Library and we're going to have our three column album name,
and that's going to be a varchar like a string,
our artist's name, again,
a varchar similar to a string,
and year we're going to use an int, an integer.
We're going to run that. So no errors was found.
So let's check to ensure our table was actually created.
Let's do select count star which should return zero as we have not inserted any rows.
Awesome. We see the zero here at the bottom,
and you can see where we executed the select count star from music library.
So let's go about the process of inserting two broads.
So I really want you to note the syntax here of how we're doing
this in this insert statement because
you'll be doing this again and again throughout our exercises.
So this is the syntax that you'll use.
So we're going to insert into our music library,
we're going to list our columns,
then we're going to use our values and we're going to use the percent sign and S,
and then we're going to actually add a comma,
and then we're going to add in the actual values that we're going to enter in.
So in this case we have a music library.
So we have an algorithm called Let it B,
our artists are The Beatles and the year that was produced was 1970.
So we're doing the same here for another album.
So we're going to insert two rows.
Let's validate that your data was actually inserted into the table,
so we're going to do a while loop and we're going to use that for printing the results.
If you were executing this query and
the Postgres shell you wouldn't really need this while loop.
But in this case we do because we're utilizing the Python library.
So if you do end up running this insert statement code more than once,
you're going to actually see duplicates of your data.
So Postgres just let you all know allows for duplicates. All right, awesome.
So we did a select star from Music Library,
and we were able to print out our results so successfully got loaded into the table.
So just for the sake of this demo I'm going to drop the table
and we're going to finally close out the connection to our database.
So that is the end of Demo 1.