All right, here is the solution for Lesson 1,
Exercise 1, Creating a Table in Postgres.
So some of these items we've actually already walked through in the demo.
So I may just quickly go over them and we'll get to the solution.
So again, we're going to import that library,
and again if you find that error, just ignore it.
We're going to create the connection to our database.
In this case, you'll see here I just connected to my local instance.
So I didn't actually need to provide any connection info,
but any connection you make just what connects its fine.
Again, we're going to get our cursor and we're going to set the auto commits to true,
and then we're going to test out other connections.
So let's set our arguments.
Just set our connections, so we're going to try to do select star from songs.
What we should expect to see is that nicely handled error, which we do.
Songs does not exist, wonderful.
So let's create that database to do our work.
So in this case, we created the database Udacity.
In my case, it already exists,
but for you it should execute the first time.
So again, we're going to close that connection
and then reconnect to that database that we created.
Then we're going get a cursor,
and we're going to set the auto commit,
all things that you saw in the demo.
So now we're ready to get going and actually create our table.
So in this case, we imagine that we're going to create
a song library in the demo we had created our music library with albums.
In this case, we're going to songs,
of all the songs that we know.
Each song has a lot of information that we could add to the song library table,
but we'll start with just the name of the song, the artist's name,
the year, and the album it was from,
and if it was a single.
So again, song title,
artist, year, album, and single.
Now, let's translate that into our create statement.
So this is really the key here.
So what we want to execute is the create table if does not exist,
and we're going to call our table, in this case,
it's songs, but you're welcome to call it anything that you feel comfortable with.
Then we're going to have a column called song title,
which is a varchar,
artist's name also varchar,
and don't feel like you need to have the exact same column names that I do.
As long as it's descriptive, it works great.
Then we're going to have a year that's an int,
we're going to have our album name, another varchar.
Then here's where it's something a little bit
interesting that we didn't show in the demo,
is that we're going to decide if it's a single,
if it's not part of an album.
We're going to say if that's true or false.
So we're going to execute that.
That should work, if no errors were found,
let's check to ensure our table was created.
So let's do a select count star from the table,
again my songs, which yours could be named anything.
Awesome, so in my case because I already created the table,
you're seeing I have three rows there.
Obviously, I didn't drop it in advance.
So in this case,
you should see zero instead I saw three.
So let's insert two rows.
So these are the two rows that we're going to insert Across the Universe,
which is a song, then The Beatles,
which is the artist's name, then the year,
and it was not a single,
and it was on the album Let It Be.
We're going to treat our second row,
and it's going to be the Beatles, Think for Yourself,
that's the song title, and then false,
that it was not a single,
and the year and then the album.
So we're going insert into the songs, the song title,
artists name, year, album name,
and single with the values.
Again, we're just going to take that information that we
had that I provided here and actually insert it.
Across the Universe, The Beatles,
1970, Let It Be as the album,
and then false it was not a single,
and then the same with the second row.
So we're going execute that,
so validate your data was inserted into table.
So again, you're going to use that while loop
so that you can actually print out the results.
So we're going to do a select star from songs.
As you can see, you're seeing something a little interesting here.
You're seeing this multiple times,
obviously because I've run
this insert statement multiple times without dropping my table,
and that's okay, because Postgres allows for duplicates.
So if I run it once, I should only see this information once.
If I run it more than once, I'm going to see this information more than once.
So just something to be aware of.
Then if you see this two rows or if you see more than two rows, that's totally fine.
So then finally after that we close out our connection.