For the remainder of this lesson,
we will focus on non-relational databases.
So what is a NoSQL Database?
So NoSQL database has a simpler design,
simpler horizontal scaling, and finer control of availability.
Data structures used are different than those in
relational database and they make some operations faster.
So NoSQL equals not only SQL.
NoSQL and non-relational are interchangeable terms.
From here on out, you'll probably only hear me say NoSQL.
Again, there are various types of NoSQL databases,
and we'll talk a little bit about that in just a minute.
So like we said in the last lesson,
NoSQL databases were created to do some of the issues faced with relational databases.
Remember all the reasons that we listed not to use a relational database?
NoSQL has been around also since the 1970s,
but they became much more popular and used during the 2000's as data sizes
increased and outages and downtime has decreased in acceptability.
So here's just a few common types of NoSQL databases.
Like I said before,
there are different NoSQL databases and different types of
implementations that will naturally align better with different use cases.
So the first one we'll discuss here is
Apache Cassandra which is what we're going to use for our examples.
This is a Partition Row store.
The data is distributed by partitions across nodes or servers,
and the data is organized in the columns and rows format.
Next, we have MongoDB,
which is a Document store.
One of the defining characteristics of
a document-oriented database is that in
addition to the Key Lookups performed by key-value store,
the database also offers an API or
query language that retrieves document based on its contents.
Think of it's basically easy to do search on documents.
Next we have DynamoDB which is a Key-Value store.
A key-value store is basically the data is
represented as a collection of key and value pairs.
Next, we have Apache HBase which is a Wide Column Store.
It also uses tables, rows, and columns,
but unlike a relational database,
the names and format of the columns can vary from row to row in the same table.
That's flexible schema that we talked about before.
Next, Neo4j.
Neo4j is a Graph Database where relationships between entities is more the focus.
With graph databases, it's all about relationships,
and the data is represented as nodes and edges.
So in this course,
we'll focus on Apache Cassandra to explain
the concepts of data modeling for NoSQL databases.
Data modeling for all NoSQL databases has a lot in common,
but each one has its own uniqueness that will play apart.
But once you have the foundation,
adapting to small changes will be very straightforward.
This is a set of terminology that is specific to Apache Cassandra.
Other NoSQL databases will use slightly different terminology,
but the concepts are the same.
So here is some of the basics of Apache Cassandra.
We have a Keyspace,
which is a collection of tables.
So in relational terms that would be a database.
We have a Table, which is a group of partitions.
We have Rows, which is a single item.
These are all very straightforward.
Let's talk about some of the really specific things to Apache Cassandra.
We have a Partition,
which is the fundamental unit of access,
it is a collection of rows,
and it is how the data is distributed.
We have a Primary Key.
The primary key is made up of a partition key and clustering columns.
Then we have Columns,
which we have clustering columns and data columns and these are the labeled elements.
So from here, you can see we're partitioning by last name because this is our partition.
We have some clustering columns around First Name and Last Name,
and then here we have some data columns,
which are just our address and email.
Again, we're going to talk about these concepts in a lot of depth in Lesson 3.
So if it seems confusing now, don't worry.