So let's talk about when to use a NoSQL database.
So if you have large amounts of data,
NoSQL was built for big data.
The more data you have and the ability to
scale out as needed to increase space and performance,
that's really what it had in mind.
If you need to horizontally scale,
you may need a NoSQL database.
The ability to add more nodes or servers to the system to increase performance.
If you need high throughput,
you may want to consider using a NoSQL database.
The ability to do fast reads and writes to the database.
You can do an insert statement quickly and also a select statement quickly.
If you need a flexible schema.
I can change my schema as necessary.
I don't have to have the same column set for each one of my rows.
If you need that kind of flexibility,
you might want to consider a NoSQL database.
If you need high availability.
If you need high availability with no downtime,
again, this is what NoSQL was built for.
That's something you may want to consider.
If you need to be able to store different data types and different datatype formats,
you may want to consider a NoSQL database.
Again, it's more flexible in that area.
If your users are distributed and you still want to have low latency to those users.
If the users of my database and my application that it
serves are geographically distributed,
and because of this I wanted to be able to serve each of my users with
a minimum amount of lag time between when they
execute a query and when they receive the response,
we may want to consider a distributed database like a NoSQL database.
So as you can see,
all the reasons to not use a relational database are the reasons to use a NoSQL database.
You can see that's not by accident.
NoSQL was built to handle the limitations that exist in relational databases.
If you know your database history,
you know that NoSQL became popular in the 2000s
as the web began to grow and data volumes increased.
NoSQL was built for big data.
NoSQL was also built to provide users with very low latency.
Just to let everyone know,
within a second delay on a website,
most folks will move to another website or app.
So here's just an example.
I just provided this to just show you
a quick example of Apache Cassandra and its performance,
and basically this is all about the linear scalability.
So a quick word about linear scalability and scalability.
So what this means is that you can add nodes and
the performance will increase in a linear fashion.
So this x-axis is the number of nodes and
the y-axis is the number of reads and writes that can be performed.
In this case, it's just writes.
So as you add more nodes,
your performance will increase in a linear fashion and you can see from this line here.
The more nodes you add,
the more you're going to be able to have client writes
to the database and this will also increase.
You can see this is actually information that was published by Netflix.