All right so let's move on to
our next demo which is creating a table with Apache Cassandra.
So here we're going to move back on to our Jupyter notebook,
and we're going to open Demo 2 for lesson 1.
So we're going to create a table.
A lot of this beginning code that we have here it's
actually going to feel pretty similar to what we just did in Exercise 1.
So in this demo we're going to walk through
the basis of creating a table in Apache Cassandra,
inserting rows, and doing the simple SQL query to validate the information.
Again we're going use a python wrapper,
and in this case it's called "Cassandra driver".
It's the python driver for Cassandra,
and more documentation can be found here.
So we're going to import the package,
even though we install it with Cassandra driver it's really just Cassandra.
To import that Python package.
Now let's create a connection to the database.
This connects to our local instance of Apache Cassandra.
Again the connection will reach out to the database and
ensure we have the correct privileges to connect.
Once we get the cluster object back,
we need to connect and then we'll create a session,
so that we can execute the queries.
Again this block of code will be pretty standard in all of our notebooks.
So we were able to connect,
let's test our connection.
We're trying to do a select star in a table that we have not yet created.
So we should expect to see a nicely handled error.
Awesome good we see an error,
but that's what we expected.
So we have not specified our keyspace yet,
keyspace is like our database.
So we need to be able to do that before we can do a select star.
So let's create that keyspace to do our work.
So in this case just ignore the replication strategy,
and the replication factor for now.
We'll talk about that in a later time,
but just know that for on a one node local instance
these will always be your strategy and your replication factor,
and just a little bit about a replication factor
that means how many times your your data is copied,
and since we're on a one node we don't want it copied
across multiple nodes because we don't have them really important.
So we're going to create our keyspace if doesn't exist,
and in this case we're going to create a keyspace called "udacity",
and then with our replication we're going to use the simple strategy and a factor of one.
So let's execute that and that ran,
and then let's connect to our keyspace.
So in this case we just need to set our key space.
This is the command here utilizing the python wrapper,
and then we connect it to the keyspace that we just created.
So compare this to how we were able to create a new session in PostgreSQL,
we're just able to set the keyspace here.
We don't need to make a new connection. It's very convenient.