So let's start creating our tables.
Let's imagine we'd like to start creating a music library of albums.
Each album has a lot of information we could use,
but we're just going to start with the album name,
artist name, and year.
But, stop, wait.
We're working with Apache Cassandra a NoSQL database.
We can't model our data and create our table without more information.
What queries will I be performing on this data?
In this case, I'd like to be able to get every album that was
released in a particular year. View this query here.
Select star from music library where year equals 1970.
Because of this, I need to be able to do a where on year.
Year will become my partition key,
and the artist name will be my clustering column to make each primary key unique.
Remember, there are no duplicates in Apache Cassandra.
So if I don't have a unique key,
it will just get overwritten.
So in this case, my table name will be music library,
my column will be album name, artist name,
year, and then here's the key, my primary key.
I'm going to partition by year and then include my artist name to make it
unique because we're imagining
that an artist doesn't create more than one album in one year.
It's just an assumption that we're making for this demo and actually may be incorrect.
But just for the sake of the demo, that's what we're assuming.
Now let's translate this information into a Create Table Statement.
For more information on the datatypes in Apache Cassandra,
you can view this document here.
Now, don't worry if this all seems a little bit confusing.
We'll spend all of Lesson 3 on these topics.
So we're going to create table if it does not exist, music_library.
Then from there, we're going to have the year which we'll represent as an int,
our artist name which we'll represent as text,
again is like string or varchar in Postgres,
our album name as text and here we're setting our primary key,
Primary key, year, and artist name,
and that needs to be in parentheses.
So we'll execute this.
So if no errors were found,
but let's check to make sure our table was created.
Let's do a select count star which should return as zero,
as we have not inserted any rows.
Now depending on the version of Apache Cassandra you have installed,
this command may actually throw an error,
or it may show the answer of zero.
This is to be expected.
Again, these types of queries aren't normally performed on large datasets
because we're just doing a demo and I just wanted to show
you that the table was created. I'm doing this.
But on a large dataset,
maybe spread across a table,
spread across thousands of nodes.
You do not want to do a select count star or a select star.
But we're just doing that for the sake of the demo.
Okay, wonderful, I did my select count star from
my music_library and I got back a count of zero.
So again, let's insert our two rows.
Very similar syntax to what we saw in Postgres, little bit different.
So we're going to insert into music_library.
So in this case, we just set up one query
variable so that we can just utilize that again and again.
We could have also done it like we did in the Postgres exercise,
but this just made a little bit cleaner.
But as you can see, we have our insert,
we have our columns listed here,
and then our values with a percent s. Then we're going to
fill those in using the session.execute,
and then our query,
and then our information that we're going to provide to
that query statements to be executed.
So every year, the artist name and the album name.
So let's validate that our data was inserted into the table.
So in this case, just for the sake of the demo,
like I said before, we're going to do a select star from the table.
But on a real production system,
we would never do this query.
Okay, and we got back our answers.
So we were successfully able to query that table and we loaded that table.
Again, because Apache Cassandra does not allow for duplicates,
I can run that insert statement as many times as I want,
we'd never get more than two rows.
So let's validate our data model with the original query.
Select star from music library where year equals 1970.
So here's my query here,
and I'm going to execute it with this fetch and execute,
and then I'm going to print my rows.
Wonderful, I got back my information that I needed.
So I have 1970, let it be and the Beatles.
For the sake of the demo,
I will drop this table.
Then we're finally going to close out this session and the cluster connection.