Before we start diving into Postgres and Apache Cassandra,
let's all get on the same page on what exactly is data modeling.
Data modeling at a high level is all about an abstraction
that organizes elements of data and how they relate to each other.
We are all so used to spreadsheets and the way data is organized in that fashion.
Who hasn't made a spreadsheet to organize their household bills or plan a trip?
Think about the process you went through to create that first set of rows and columns.
That is data modeling.
The process of creating data models for an informational system.
Data modeling can easily translate to database modeling,
as this is the essential end state.
Data modeling can be considered an abstract process.
But as you continue the process of creating data models,
you'll begin modeling the data for a particular informational system.
Data modeling can easily be called database modeling,
as this will be your final state or the home of your data.
The process of data modeling is to organize data into a database system to
ensure that your data is persisted and easily usable by you in your organization.
Data modeling is a process to support both your business and your user applications.
Let's discuss the difference between these two needs.
Let's say we owned an online store,
we will need to store that data so that we
can understand how much stock we sold of a particular item.
This is a business process,
and we'll also need to store information about our customer as
they'd log onto our website, a user application.
To begin a data modeling process,
the team must gather requirements from the application team,
the business users, and our end users to understand that data must
be retained and served as a business or the end-users.
First we need to map out that our data must be stored and
persisted and how that data will relate to each other.
Next we want to focus on conceptual data modeling.
The process starts or process of doing
actual data modeling starts with conceptual data modeling with entity mapping.
This can be done actually by hand or by using many tools to do this work.
Conceptual data modelings is just as it sounds.
This is mapping the concepts of the data that you have or will have.
Again, think about the Excel spreadsheets you've made in the past.
The moment where you jot down some notes and titles to call your columns,
is like conceptual data modeling.
Think of this as a giant white-boarding session with all the members of your team.
The relationship between your data will be organized in this process.
Think about our online store.
We can imagine having a customer box,
connected to our sales box,
connected to our inventory box.
Here, when I say box,
I'm really referring to something like this,
this is an entity mapping diagram.
Next will be doing logical data modeling.
From their, logical data modeling is done where the contextual models are mapped
to logical models using the concept of tables, schemas, and columns.
Now we have to start thinking more practically and move
those boxes and arrows we drew it on the whiteboard to tables with columns.
Let's think about the box we created for our customer.
Naturally, each customer table will have columns such as name,
address, and phone number.
From there, physical data modeling is done transforming
the logical data model to the databases data definition language or DDL,
to be able to create the databases,
the tables, and the schemas.
Now we need to start writing code.
We will be writing our DDLs to create tables in the way that the database understands.
Every database does this about 99 percent the same,
but always with a few tweaks.
You'll need to Google when working with a new database.
So a DDL, again,
that definition is the Data Definition Language.
In this course, we're going to focus on the physical data model
to create DDLs in relational and non-relational databases.
We're going to focus on combination of
biological and physical data modeling in this class,
with both Postgres and Apache Cassandra.