So now that we understand what data modeling is,
let's talk about why data modeling is important.
So data organization is critical.
So the organization of your data for your applications is extremely important.
Organizing data determines later data use.
Having a well thought out and organized data model
is critical to how that data can later be used.
Queries that could have been straightforward and simple might become
complicated queries if data modeling is not well thought out.
You don't want to have to do a join on four tables just to get a customer e-mail,
when they could have easily added that column to my customer table.
That's just a simple example to try to get you thinking about how we want to
make sure our queries are simple and straightforward as much as we can.
Next, begin prior to building out applications,
business models, and analytical models.
So the data modeling process begins prior to building out applications,
business logic, and analytical models.
It's definitely an iterative process.
So you want to make sure that your starting
data modeling early with half of your organization,
it's probably not something you can do alone to be successful.
This is not something you want to leave until the last minute.
Again, it is an iterative process.
Having flexibility will help as new information becomes available.
Maybe you'll need to add a column to a table that you had not foreseen.
Maybe you want to add a column to your customer table
or create a new table that focuses on new customers.