Let's talk about when to use a relational database.
So next, we will review when to use a relational database,
and we're going to go over this in the next few slides.
So the advantage of using
a relational database and we're going to go through quite a few options here.
So the first one here is just the ease of use,
and especially of using SQL.
The ease of writing queries in SQL,
it's a very common database query language that is very straightforward.
Next is the ability to do JOINS.
That's one of the reasons we'd want to use a relational database.
The ability to use JOINS,
combining more than one table on a common key or to get more information.
This is something that is unique to relational databases and makes it very powerful.
The ability to do aggregations and analytics,
the ability to do this on your data,
to do the analytics and the aggregations.
This is really what a relational database was built for,
along with being a persistent datastore.
GROUP BY, ORDER BY,
SOME are all examples that we're not going to go into this course,
but they are good examples of aggregations.
If you have smaller data volumes,
then using a relational database is probably a good idea.
If you have a smaller data volume, essentially,
if you don't have big data,
you can use a relational database for simplicity.
Next, it's easier to change business requirements.
Relational databases make it easy to change business requirements,
as you can perform ad hoc queries on your database with ease.
Again, you'll have the flexibility to run
many different queries and new queries on your data.
Think of a new query, go try it out,
as long as you have permissions, of course.
Modeling the data, not modeling queries.
With relational databases, you'll be modeling the data itself,
not modeling your data to the queries.
Data modeling is independent in some regards to your queries,
especially when compared to non-relational databases.
We'll learn more about this later in the next lesson.
You'll also get the added benefit of secondary indexes.
So what do we mean by secondary indexes?
Let's review on the next slide.
So in this case, another fundamental concept is the idea of secondary indexes.
You would like to efficiently structure your data
by an index that is not your primary key.
You can add a secondary index for quick searching.
In this example, our primary key is on city.
That is what we would normally use in our queries.
Let's say this here. Let's say imagine we normally do our queries using the city,
but we find we're frequently using the country code in our queries.
We can create a secondary index to speed up the retrieval process.
Be aware, secondary indexes require additional resources.
Let's go back to the advantages of using relational databases.
Here, maybe the most important one of all is the fact that
relational databases add the ability to have ACID transactions.
The benefit of ACID transactions means that you'll have strong data integrity,
basically that your data is correct.
What do we mean by ACID transactions?
Let's look at this more in depth.