We could spend a whole lesson or even a college
semester on Advanced Relational Database topic,
but let's do a brief introduction to ACID,
what it stands for, and why it's important.
You might have heard of ACID transactions before,
but if you haven't, now you will.
So the ACID properties are properties of a database transaction intended to
guarantee validity even in the event of errors or power failures.
A good example is to think of transferring funds in a bank transaction.
Multiple steps must all occur for this to be successful and correct.
All those steps are considered one transaction.
ACID transactions ensure data integrity,
and that the given answer that you get back is correct.
In the context of databases,
a sequence of database operations that satisfy the ACID properties,
that these can be perceived as a single logical operation,
is what is called a transaction.
Let's walk through each one of these properties.
Atomicity, consistency, isolation, and durability.
Let's walk through each of the term.
Atomicity, the whole transaction is processed or nothing is processed.
This is all about all or nothing.
Let's think of a banking transaction of
transferring money from my checking to my savings account.
This is a two-step process.
Money must be removed from my checking and added to my savings in one block.
If we need not do this in a block or an ACID transaction,
I could end up removing money from
my checking account and then never deposing it in my savings account.
Consistency, only transactions that abide by
constraints and rules is written into the database.
Otherwise, the database keeps previous state.
This is very straightforward.
If you've defined a column as a Boolean,
let's say a true or false,
you'll be unable to enter in a value for that row in that column that equals "Hello".
That's a string. It will be rejected and that transaction will not complete.
Isolation, transactions are processed independently and securely.
Order does not matter.
If multiple queries are performing actions,
even in a concurrent state,
those queries will continue to interact with the data in
the same way as if the queries had been run sequentially.
When a query comes in the row or the rows it affects,
will lock until the transaction is complete.
From there, other queries are not able to interact with this data.
This ensures the correctness of the data for
multiple users running queries against the database.
Durability, completed transactions are
saved to the database even in cases of system failure.
This definition is a bit confusing.
It seems impossible. So let's break it down.
Durability guarantees that once a transaction has been committed,
that's the key, it will remain committed,
even in the case of a system failure,
power outage, or crash.
This usually means that completed transaction or
its effects are recorded in non-volatile memory.
Essentially, what this means is all goes back to the fact that
our database is a persistent data store.
Once the transaction has happened and it is complete,
then even if you were to pull the plug on the database,
when you plug it back in, that data will be there.