We've just reviewed when to use a Relational Database,
but let's talk about when not to use a Relational Database.
So before we do some review,
let's go over some basics.
So let's say if you have large amounts of data
or you need to be able to store data in different data formats,
Relational Databases are not distributed databases because of this,
they can only scale vertically by adding more storage in the machine itself.
You're limited to how much you can scale,
and how much data you can store on one machine.
You can not add more machines like you can in NoSQL databases.
If you need high throughput or fast read,
this is when you should not use
a Relational Database while acid transaction bring benefits,
they also slow down the process of reading and writing data.
If you need very fast reads and writes
using a Relational Database may not suit your needs.
If you need a flexible schema,
flexible schemas can allow for columns to be
added that do not have to be used by every row,
and this saves disk space.
If you meet high availability,
the fact that Relational Databases are not distributed,
and even when they are,
they have a coordinator worker architecture,
they have a single point of failure.
When the database goes down a fail over to a backup system must happen,
and this takes time.
If you need to be able to scale horizontally.
Horizontal scalability, is the ability to add
more machines or nodes to a system to increase performance,
and add space for the data.
We will go over these last two points in a moment.
These issues that we're seeing here are what lead to
the creation of non-relational and NoSQL databases.
High availability, this describes
the database where there's very little downtime of the system,
and it's always on and functioning,
so highly available system has very little or even no downtime.
Horizontally Scalable, ability to add servers to the system.
Scalability of a database means that I can add more nodes or servers to a system,
and the performance in the space of the system will increase.
Many traditional databases especially Relational Databases cannot add additional servers.