So let's talk about the relational database we'll be using in
this course for relational data modeling exercises and demos.
What is PostgreSQL?
The PostgreSQL is an open-source object-relational database system
and it uses and builds on the SQL language.
So it uses inbuilt from the SQL database language by providing
various features that reliably store in scale, complicated data workloads.
PostgreSQL syntax is different than other relational database SQL syntax.
But this is just a small note.
All relational and non-relational databases tend to have
their own SQL syntax and operations you can perform.
There are different between types of implementations.
Most just need a quick Google Search to understand the difference.
This note is just to make you aware of this.
Data modeling concepts are what you need to focus on in these lessons,
not so much on the syntax