My name is Ben Goldberg,
and I'll be your instructor for this course.
Throughout these lessons, I'll be introducing you to the concept of data pipelines,
and how you can use them to accelerate your career as a data engineer.
This course will focus on applying the data pipeline concepts you learn through
an open source tool from Airbnb called Apache Airflow.
Once you've completed this course,
you will be ready to apply these skills in your career as a data engineer.
Before we get started, I want to tell you a bit about myself.
Most of my career has been centered around data engineering of one kind or another.
I spent the beginning of my career working on computer vision
teaching airborne systems to understand and parse the world around them.
I worked at an artificial intelligence startup that was able to
transform raw datasets into written language,
which is where I had my first introduction to
many of the concepts we're going to cover in this course.
I'm currently located in Chicago where I'm a staff engineer at SpotHero.
At SpotHero, I founded, built,
and lead our data engineering team.
I'm also a contributor to Apache Airflow,
and one of the three original contributors to the Airflow Kubernetes executor.
The approaches we're going to cover in this course represents the best practices
that I've learned through my day-to-day work as a data engineer,
and through collaborating with colleagues in the space.