So now that we've learned about schedules,
I want to talk about one of my favorite features of airflow and that feature is
how airflow has so many operators that are shipped along with it.
Many common data engineering problems can be solved using the provided operators.
In the beginning of this lecture,
we discussed an example,
a removed data from S3 to Redshift.
As you can see on this diagram,
airflow comes out of the box with an operator that can perform this work.
All you have to do is correctly instantiate the operator with your desired parameters.
We'll walk through an example of this in an exercise shortly.
Remember our definition of a graph from earlier in the lesson,
every graph is made up of nodes and then edges,
which are these arrows between the nodes.
These are the edges. An airflow DAGs are nodes or tasks,
so these are the tasks, A,
B, C, D, and E. The ordering dependencies between those tasks are the edges of the graph.
Task dependencies can be described programmatically in
airflow using the double carrot operator.
So, these can be referred to as chevrons carrots.
I'll try to refer to them using the phrase carrot, so double carrot.
So, if I say A, then double carrot B, in airflow code,
that means that task A will be executed and run before task B.
If we look at our nodes here,
this is the description of exactly what's happening.
A will be run and executed before B.
Likewise, if I flip those carrots the other direction,
this would say that B comes before A.
In this example, we've defined two tasks: hello_world_task and goodbye_world_task.
Then, we use the double carrot operator to tell airflow
at the hello_world_task comes before goodbye_world_task.
So again, we have a hello_world_task and a goodbye_world_task,
and we've omitted some of the code here for clarity.
But you can see down here that I've told the airflow, "Hey,
I want hello_world_task to come before goodbye_world_task".
Alternatively, you can use the function call
set_downstream and the other function calls set_upstream functions if you prefer.
That being said, idiomatic or normal
airflow code that you would see would use these double carrot operators.
In this class, we'll ask that you use
the double carrot operators rather than set_downstream and set_upstream.
But I wanted to make sure that you were aware of what they are,
so that if you see that on other people's code, you know what they mean.
Here's an example of what that would look like if you use encode.
So this is the same as the previous example, hello_world set_downstream goodbye_world.