Okay, so I'm going to conclude.
Before we finished out here,
I want to go through one;
final demonstration, and this is going to
put together all the concepts that we've just reviewed.
That this lesson, we've been talking about a [inaudible] company and
an ELT process to identify our most highly traffic locations.
What's build an Airflow DAG that allows us to perform this analysis.
Before we begin, we need to set up a connection Redshift to Airflow.
So let's go ahead and take a look at how that works.
The first thing I'm going to do, is I'm going to go back to Airflow.
Again, turn off demo five.
Then, I'm going to actually pull up the code in my code editor here.
So, we have a little bit more going on here between line 26 to 41,
and this looks pretty different.
It's no longer a Hello World DAG.
On line 13, we have a function that says load_data _to_redshift,
although we still just have our basic DAG definition here for
lesson 1: Demo 6 with a start_dated now.
So what we're going to do here is essentially create a portion of an ETL process.
So the first thing we're going to do is we're going to set up our PostgresOperator.
Again, just to clarify,
I know it's a little confusing that we're working with
Redshift but using the PostgresOperator,
but Postgres and Redshift are interoperable from the perspective of Airflow.
So even if that's a little bit confusing,
don't worry, Postgres will work just fine.
So it's going to ask us for a connection ID,
which we haven't created yet.
So before we can continue,
we need to go back to Airflow and actually create a connection to Redshift.
So we're going to go back to this UI.
We're going to go to the Admin drop-down here.
I'm going to go to Connections,
just like we did earlier.
We're going to go to the Create tab.
Now, we're going to be filling out slightly different fields here.
My connection ID is going to be Redshift.
The connection type is going to be Postgres.
Now, again, just want to re-emphasize,
I know this is confusing,
and it's not Redshift, but you want to use Postgres connection type for this to work.
Next, you're going to get the host to your Redshift instance.
You're going to give, the schema is the database that you're going to be using.
In my case, the database is called Udacity.
Use your login information.
So my username is bgoldberg.
The password, I'm going to get from my password manager.
I'm going to copy that here and then, specify port 5439.
I'm just going to put this up for just another moment.
So connection ID needs to be Redshift.
This is the most important part.
Connection type is Postgres.
You specified the host.
We specified our database name as the Schema,
using the username that you provided and your password,
and you specify the port as 5439.
Then you're going to click Save.
We're not going to edit to last pass,
but we've created that, and we can scroll down in this list.
We can see we have a Redshift here.
So we're going to go back to the main page,
and we're going to then return to our code example here,
and we're going to finish this up.
So now, that we have a Postgres connection ID called redshift,
we can replace this.
You also need to give this task ID.
So we're going to call this create_table.
Next, we're going to define a copy task.
So this is a Python operator,
and we're going to use the function we defined above, load_data_to_redshift.
So we're going to say task_id=copy.
In fact, we'll call that copy_to_redshift,
a little more descriptive, copy_to_redshift.
Then we're going to give it a DAG,
and we actually need to get the DAG to this operator as
well and then we need to give it the python_callable.
In this case, that's equal to load_data_to_redshift.
Finally, we have to define a proper task ordering.
So we're going to create the table and then we're going to run in
the copy task. I'm going to save this.
One more thing I just want to note,
I've provided SQL to this PostgresOperator here.
Typically, you can define the SQL in-line here.
But because the purpose of this class is to review
Airflow and not to actually build out SQL statements,
I've actually provided all the SQL that we're going to be using in a separate file.
If you're interested in the SQL that I'm running,
you can open the files sql.py, and have a look.
For now, we're not going to review it,
I just want to let you know where you can find it.
Okay. So now, that we've defined our DAG,
we're going to come back into Airflow and refresh.
I'm going to go over to extras to the demo 6,
and click on the code view,
and we're just going to review the code to make sure that it looks good.
So we have our load data statement here.
We've got our DAG defined.
We have our create_table operator.
Excuse me, our create_table task.
We have our copy_task,
and we have a create_table coming before copy_task.
So with that in mind, we can go back.
You can turn this on, and jump out of here.
I don't have a schedule settlement DAG,
so I'm going to need to run it manually. We're going to do that.
Now, we're going to wait. We're going to jump in here.
You can see that one of these tasks is queued.
So earlier, we had a question about would it
be possible to see an example where things
don't happen at the same time, and this is an example.
So this hasn't happened yet.
copy_to_redshift, it has a dependency,
so it hasn't run yet, and now, they both executed.
So we've created the table,
I've copied the redshift.
To actually see the logs from those statements,
you can click on them. Go to View Log.
If you scroll down,
airflow will actually log the SQL that it executed,
so you can see what was being run against the database.
All right. Likewise, if I go back,
you can see the copy_to_redshift,
and you need to log there as well,
and you can see exactly what was running.
It's worth mentioning that if you're interested,
you can jump into Redshift yourself via PSQL or another database interface,
and you can actually see the code that's there.
So, that's a demonstration.
I hope you guys have fun trying this demonstration on your own tonight as homework.
Again, I just want to reiterate if you had extended line for
about 20 minutes to get feedback, that would be great.
Thank you again for your time today.
Really, I had a great time walking through this slide with you.