Okay. So now that we've talked about Airflow,
we've had a couple of quizzes,
I thought it'd be fun to jump into our first demonstration.
So, I'm going to move over to coding window here and show you our first demonstration.
So, this is a DAG.
I'm going to zoom in here so this is a little easier to see.
This is our first DAG.
What you can see here is on line 12,
we have the definition of our DAG,
and we're instantiating the DAG which was imported from airflow on line four.
There are two components that every DAG must have.
The first one is a name.
So, we're naming our DAG "lesson1.demo1."
The next thing every DAG must have is a start date.
In this case, we don't really care what
our start date is because we're just doing a "Hello, World!",
so I'm going to set the start_date to datetime.datetime.now,
which is equivalent to whatever the time is right now in my time zone.
Now that we've got that DAG defined,
there is no actual work involved with this.
It has no task to perform.
If I go back to the UI,
and I'm going to zoom in here as well so it's a little easier to see,
and I go to "lesson1.demo1" and click on it and go to the Graph View, well, first,
we can see here in our Tree View,
we just have a DAG, there's no nodes involved.
If I go to the Graph View,
you can see airflow is confused because there are no tasks.
So, we're going to go back and we're going to define a task.
The first thing we're going to do is uncomment this code.
You can see here that we have a task ID,
python_callable and a DAG.
These are the arguments to our operator.
We're going to talk in detail about what operators are shortly,
but for now, this is how you define a node in our graph.
We're going to give this a task ID.
I'm going to call this "greet_task",
and we haven't defined a python_callable,
so I'm going to leave this for now,
and the DAG that this belongs to is the DAG that we defined above.
So, this DAG on line 23 references the DAG that we instantiated on line 12.
Now, we need to define a "Hello, World!"
function. So, I'm going to define a "greet function."
For this function, we're going to do "logging.info("Hello World!").
If you feel more comfortable writing a print statement you could also do that,
but if we use the logger,
we actually get to see the output in the Airflow's logs.
I'm going to go down to the python_callable,
and I'm going to put in "greet", and I'm going to save.
Now, Airflow should pick up our changes here automatically.
It can take anywhere from 15 seconds to 30 seconds,
sometimes up to a minute for Airflow to pick up your changes.
So, if you save your file and it doesn't automatically show up in the Airflow UI,
that's okay, give it a little bit of time.
So, to get from this main screen to the code definition,
I can hover over the code view,
the lightning bolt icon here and click on that.
The first thing I'm going to do is check.
Does Airflow see the same thing that I see? It looks right.
I can actually see the code that Airflow is loaded.
So, on line 11 and 12,
we have our "greet" function.
On lines 23 to 27,
we have our "greet_task",
which we defined, and then we are good to run it.
I'm going to go back to the main screen,
and this is the first step you always have to take with Airflow.
We need to toggle the DAG on.
There's a little switch over here.
Now the DAG is on. We need to actually now tell the Airflow to run the DAG.
To do that, I'm going to click this "Trigger DAG" button over here, this "Play" button.
It's going to prompt me and say,
"Are you sure you want to do that?"
I am. I'm going to go ahead and click "Okay."
The first thing you're going to notice is that now we have
the timestamp of the last run in this column here.
So, this tells us the last time this DAG ran.
We also have this light green orb in this DAG
runs column and this tells us that the DAG is running but not yet complete.
Over here, the recent task column is completely empty.
I'm going to refresh the page now and you're going to see something slightly different.
Let me check my logs here real quick.
So, when something goes wrong with Airflow,
the first thing we're going to want to do typically is check the logs.
We just want to make sure everything is running.
I'm going to try replacing this docker-compose file
real quick and see if we can get that to work.
Now it's down. Try that one more time.
Try starting it back up and let's see if we can get it to run.
While this starts up, what we should be seeing here,
we have this green running orb,
this will eventually move in in success column,
where it'll be dark green.
Over here, our tasks will have the same color scheme and we'll progress from.
[inaudible]
Okay. Because I restarted docker-compose,
we're going to restart a refresh.
Can you guys can see the screen okay?
We can see if we [inaudible]
Great. Okay. I'm going to turn the DAG on,
and then we're going to go ahead and click the "Play" button.
All right. This is exactly what we should see. It's not working.
I apologize again about the technical difficulties,
that's the rule of live demos that something must always go wrong.
So I'm going to refresh,
and you can see now that our task has moved in the success column.
So, the "Hello, World!" task is run.
We're going to look at the logs here in just a second,
but before we go, we're going to look at this bright green orb here.
The DAG is still in the running state and it just takes
the scheduler just a moment to move the DAG in to the completed state.
Now if we look here, we have this dark green success,
and I can actually click on this task and it takes me to
the execution of that task so that we're in a Task Instances page.
Likewise, I can also click on this specific DAG run,
and then I can see information about its particular run.
But perhaps, the easiest way of all to get information about
runs is to actually click on the DAG on the left here,
which takes you into this Tree View.
This shows you all the historical runs of our DAG.
You can see here we have one task that's run,
and I can click on this task,
the "greet_task" that we define,
so it should be a little bit familiar.
Remember that here we defined a "greet_task" on line 23 to 27,
and this name "greet_task" correlates to the name you'll see in the UI here.
So, we have one task in our DAG.
I can see the logs by clicking on this.
Again, I clicked on the little green box here,
and this screen has a lot of information on it.
It can be really overwhelming.
There are only a couple of things we're going to worry about in this class,
and to be honest with you,
the most important one from my perspective is this "View Log" button.
This will actually show you what the task did and what it logged.
We're going to click on that button and it's going to take you to this page,
where it's going to show you all the logs associated with the run.
Again, there's a lot of information here because Airflow is
showing its logs in addition to whatever you logged as well.
But if we look down here,
you can see we've printed out "Hello, World!
So, on this line,
you can actually see us print out "Hello, World!"
That's because here on line 12,
we logged "Hello, World!"