So, now that we have had a quiz,
we're going to modify our DAG with a schedule and date and maximum active runs.
Let me go ahead and walk through a demo for you.
So, let me show that lesson one.
Lesson two demo one is off.
Then I'm going to return to my DAGs over
here and I'm going to open up lesson tow demo two.
All right, so we have our DAG here starting on line 35.
We're going to fill in some information on this DAG.
The first thing we're going to do is we're going to give it an end date.
So, we're going to give it an end date of December 1st.
So, I'm going to say datetime dot datetime 2018,
December 1st, and then I'm going to make sure that I say I have zero, zero, zero, zero.
Again, that's hours, minutes, seconds, and microseconds.
Then I'm going to go down and set a schedule interval.
So for this schedule interval I'm going to use monthly.
All right. So now we have a monthly schedule interval.
Finally, I'm going to give it a max active run setting.
I'm going to cover this in just a second but I just want to reiterate,
we have a start date and an end date.
So what we should see here is that our DAG should run for starting on January 1st,
2018, and should conclude on December 1st, 2018.
I've also said that the schedule interval should be monthly,
so we should have 12 total runs.
Finally, what is max active runs?
We haven't covered this in the lecture because this is
a particular setting on our schedule.
Max active runs is an argument to
our DAG constructor which tells Airflow that
I only want one of this DAG to run at a time.
I'll help you understand this parameter a little
bit more when we actually visualize this as in the run.
Okay. So flip to edit a DAG,
just going to take a look through here.
Everything looks good. We have our settings
correct so we've saved and now we're going to open Airflow backup.
So we're going to open lesson two demo three,
pull up the code to make sure that my changes have been reflected.
I can see here that we have 2018-2019 except for this is the wrong DAG, sorry about that.
Meant to click on lesson two demo two,
so make sure I'm on the right row this time.
I'm going to click on the code view,
scroll down a bit here and you can see we have our to-dos filled in here.
So a monthly interval,
December 1st, and max active runs set to 1.
So I'm going to turn to my DAGs menu,
and I turn-on lesson two demo two.
I wait a few moments and refresh the page and
we can see that Airflow has already started to schedule our DAG.
Click into our DAG and you can
see here that Airflow has picked up that we have a monthly schedule.
So that's correct. We can see that Airflow is actually starting to run our DAGs.
So I'm going to refresh the page,
and we have our first monthly run complete.
So this took place on,
you can see the run up there 2018-01-01,
so this is our run for the 1st of January, 2018.
If I refresh the page,
we have our second run happening.
I'm going to refresh one more time here.
I want to get these to turn, there we go,
turned gray and then we'll get it to turn green.
Great. So we can see we have a second run here for February 1.
So again, you can see in this black box,
it says run 2018-02-01.
So this is a run for February 1st.
So Airflow is currently back-filling the history of all of these runs.
Keep refreshing and so what's really interesting about this is that you
can just roll over each one of these to see Airflow working on its back-fill.
So we talked about max active runs.
I come back over here, you can see this variable, max active runs.
What does that mean? What does this do?
So max active runs tells Airflow,
it's okay to parallelize my tasks.
So in this particular case,
we have four tasks,
but I don't want you to parallelize runs of my DAGs.
So I don't want the run for say January 1st and February 1st to happen at the same time.
This can be important because some analyses depend on data from the previous month.
So I want my January analysis to complete before my February analysis begins.
Max active runs lets you control that.
If you'd like, there are advanced features for the actual tasks and
operators within your DAG where you can say that you don't want
more than one copy of a particular DAG running at once but
often times this kind of parallelization can really speed up your DAG.
So we're not going to watch the execution of this DAG for too much longer here.
I want to see if I can catch an example of it
actually parallelizing the execution of our DAGs.
So here you can see the light green,
this is running, okay?
So I can see here that
the create trips table and the create stations table tasks are running at the same time.
So we're seeing parallelization of our tasks.
Likewise, I can go to my graph view and I can actually see all of
the runs and the status of
those runs and what's really nice is you can see the date built-in here.
So January 1st, February 1st,
March 1st, so on and so forth.