Hopefully everybody had a good time working in exercise two.
I'm going to review the solution with you real quick.
So, we already saw in my demonstration,
how to add a monthly interval.
Major difference between the exercise and what I
demonstrated was the frequency of the runs and how long it was running for.
So, I'm going to go ahead,
move back to the code.
I'm going to pull up the solution here.
So, we're looking at lesson two, exercise two.
Okay. So, in the code,
I asked for you to set an end date, February first.
So, your code should look something like this, February one.
Secondly, I asked for a schedule interval of monthly,
and I wanted to use at the max active runs to one.
Once you've done that, very similar to what you saw me show in the Airflow UI,
you would have pulled up the Airflow UI.
Seen lesson two, exercise two,
you would've turned it on.
Without clicking the run button,
you didn't need to click this.
Airflow automatically would have backfilled for both January and February.
You could click into the DAG and you can see a couple of columns here.
Click into the graph view and you can see a graph of those runs.
Now, it's worth mentioning.
If you didn't want to just run through February,
if you wanted to run through the end of 2018 or even to today,
you're more than welcome to do that.
For the sake of speed,
we had you only do a couple of backfills,
but there's nothing wrong with adding more.