Now, we'll learn more about data partitioning and data pipelines
and how a good data partitioning strategy can make our pipelines faster,
more reliable and easier to test.
First, let's define what data partitioning is.
Data partitioning is the process of isolating data to
be analyzed by one or more attributes such as time,
which we just reviewed in the previous lesson,
logical type, or data size.
In the previous lecture, we spoke in detail about pipelines schedules,
which are a form of time partitioning.
Not only are schedules great for reducing
the amount of data our pipelines have to process,
but they also help us guarantee that we can be
timing guarantees that our data consumers may need.
In this section, we'll learn more about partitioning by logical type or data size.
We'll also explore the reasons why data partitioning is
such an important consideration in the design and creation of our pipelines.
Conceptually related data can be partitioned into
discrete segments and then processed further from there.
This process of separating data based on
this conceptual relationship is called logical partitioning.
In our partial example,
we've loaded trip and stations data.
We have tripped data and stations data.
But we loaded them independently.
So, we have two tasks.
We have an estimator redshift for
the trip data and an estimator redshift for the stations data.
If we loaded both trip and stations data
together at the same time and one or both of those tests failed,
it would be hard to debug than if we had just loaded each data set independently.
That being said, if we were to analyze
both our trips data and stations data to produce a single output.
So, let's say that this was going to create one output.
That would be a totally valid thing to do to combine them.
With logical partitioning, the thing to keep in mind is
that unrelated things belong in separate steps.
Consider your dependencies and separate processing around those boundaries.
So, as partitioning separates data for processing
based on desired or required storage limits.
So, in this example,
we have our estimated redshift operator and we might actually only want to look at say,
one gigabyte of data at a time.
Many events streaming systems such as Amazon's Firehose can be configured to
write data out to key stores like Amazon S3 when a particular size has been hit.
This is particularly important with airflow as
airflow workers will have limited amount of memory available for processing.
As we reviewed in Lesson one,
airflow workers only have the amount of
memory on their individual machine available to them.
They can't pull memory like systems such as Apache Spark.
In the above diagram,
the airflow test running on worker is handling one gigabyte of data at a time.
We can probably safely assume that our workers have more than one gigabyte of RAM.
So, we can be certainly can process this much data.
Additionally, processing the small amount of data maybe much faster
than handling all of data available all at once.
Size partitioning is critical to understand when working
with large data sets, especially with airflow.
Airflow workers don't pull memory like some data processing frameworks.
If your airflow worker has 32 gigabytes of RAM,
which is substantial for some machines that you might actually see
used and you tried to load a 100 gigabyte data set,
the worker is going to kill the task.
If the worker kills a task,
you'll be unable to analyze that data and will likely have
to redesign your DAG or repartition your data.
This is one of the reasons we recommend you use airflow to trigger
dataframe works like Spark to process large data sets.
The reason that I say you may have to redesign your DAG is because if
you built your DAG with the assumption that it can handle all the data in memory,
the likelihood is your code's going to have to
change to read only a little bit of data at a time.
So, in these types of situations,
we even need to partition the data by
size into say those one gigabyte chunks like you saw on
that first slide or you may want to trigger
an external processing framework like Spark to actually work with these larger data sets.