So now, we're going to do one more demo.
This demo, I'm going to show you how to modify our DAG to load data
month by month instead of loading all of data all at once,
this is a form of time partitioning that we can apply to our DAG.
So, in the previous example,
if you actually look at the code, we've got to pull up.
So, we're back in Lesson 2 Demo 2,
whenever left this screen.
So, if I actually look at the code that was being
executed when I say load the trips data from S3 to Redshift,
I'm going to go ahead and view the log,
we can see here that it's just copying all the data.
The data is unpartitioned,
this is all the data for 2018.
So now, I'm going to go ahead and fix that.
First, I'm going to turn off Lesson 2 Demo 2,
then we're going to turn on Lesson 2 Demo 3 in just a moment.
So, real quick, I'm going to jump into Demo 3,
and this demo is slightly modified from what you've seen in the past.
So, when you guys do exercise three,
you'll actually be modifying the code to change
the time frame that the data is loaded on to be month-by-month in Redshift.
In this example though,
I'm actually going to modify our SQL command to analyze the data month by month,
so you're going to have a slightly different exercise.
So, what we have right now is a location traffic task.
This task has an ID,
a DAG and reasoning the Redshift connection,
pretty standard so far.
Finally, we have this SQL statement down here.
So, this may look a little confusing.
What you're seeing here is a Python formatting string.
We have sql.LOCATION_TRAFFIC_SQL.
So, if we look at this command,
if you're curious what it is,
we can open that code.
Open it in the file,
and you can see down here,
we have LOCATION_TRAFFIC_SQL, so you can see
exactly what the LOCATION_TRAFFIC_SQL is doing.
Dropping the table, creating it.
Then it's creating a table by performing
a select from counts on the number of departures and number of arrivals.
But what if I just wanted to do those selects
based on data from a particular time period?
Say, for the time period of this run.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to render in
the SQL statement that we were just looking at here, this LOCATION_TRAFFIC_SQL,
so I'm going to render in this LOCATION_TRAFFIC_SQL right here,
that's what the string is doing so far.
So so far, we haven't really done anything.
All we've done is created a string that has
the SQL statement that we've already seen before.
What I want to do is add a where clause so that we're
only looking at data for time periods of interest.
So first, I'm going to say where and then we're
going to have to figure out exactly what the datetime is.
So, I think I need to look at the actual name of the field,
so the name of the field is end time,
we're going to do it by end time.
So, I'm looking at the trips table, we're going to say,
Where end time is greater than,
and this syntax can be a little confusing,
and I'm going to explain this in just a moment,
where the end time is greater than previous run.
So, previous ds stands for the last time this DAG ran,
and we want the end time
to be less than the next time the DAG is going to run.
So, real quick, let's review this one more time.
So, we want to run this LOCATION_TRAFFIC_SQL,
but we only want to run our analysis where the end time is greater than the runtime of
our previous execution of our DAG and
the end time is less than the execution of our next DAG run.
How did I know what these fields are?
Where do these come from?
So, if you remember from lesson one,
we talked about templating our DAGs.
So, I'm going to jump back to the browser and open up my API reference.
So, you can find this API reference in your lesson one and its exercises,
and we can see here I'm using previous ds and next ds.
Previous ds will give us the previous execution data of a DAG in the format year, month,
date, and next ds will give us the next execution date in the format year, month, date.
So, I want to use these two variables.
If we go back to SQL,
why do we have four of these brackets instead of two?
That's pretty strange.
The reason that we have four brackets here is that
we're going to be formatting this twice,
so this looks a little confusing.
So first, we're going to run
the Python format which is going to insert the SQL statement.
That's going to remove two of these brackets,
but we still need Airflow to inject the execution date,
previous and next execution date into the SQL statement when it runs.
So, now that we've updated this,
I'm going to save and go back to Airflow and try running my DAG.
So, we're going to turn on Lesson 2 Demo 3,
I'm going to refresh, Airflow should start running a here shortly.
So, you can see it's a resorted to the tests.
We're going to jump into Lesson 2 Demo 3,
and we can see,
in our graph view that it's already starting to create
the trips table and now it's loading the data from S3 to Redshift.
So, now we're onto the new updated calculate location traffic task.
So, it's currently running.
We're going to let that finish and now it's complete.
So, let's take a look at how it rendered out those dates.
So, I'm going to click on calculate_location_traffic,
then I'm going to go up to "View Log"
or I could look at "Rendered" let's pull up Rendered.
We scroll down, we can see that we have begin and we have nowhere.
But if we go to Log, we should see that in there.
So, you can see in our statement here,
the formatting is a little off,
I apologize for that, but you can see that this is the SQL statement in our SQL file,
which is the one we've already run a number of times before,
but we also have this new where clause,
where end time is greater than 2017 December 1st,
and end time is less than 2018 February 1st.
So, this would give us the data that we actually need to process.