All right. I hope everyone had fun working on the exercise.
We're going to take a quick look at the solution.
So, let me open it up.
I'm going to go down to my solutions.
Lesson two, exercise one. All right.
So, as we take a look at the solution,
we're going to recognize that your code looks a little bit different from mine.
So, we're loading the stations' data,
as well as the trip data.
If we go down and take a look at the operators,
we can see just like in mine,
you have a create_trips_table, copy_trips_task.
The difference is that you don't have a traffic calculation task,
and instead you're loading a stations_table and a copy_stations_task.
I asked you to run the DAG without this second line here first.
Then, to add the second line,
where we have create_stations_table happen,
and then the copy_stations_task.
With both of those changes in place,
you were able to see the difference in the runs between both of those decks,
which again you should have ended up with something that looks similar to this.
However, you would've had creating the stations_table,
and then finishing the stations_table.