Why in creating a new DAG for every feature change
become cumbersome as feature changes or bugs happen all the time?
The answer to that question is yes,
definitely it can be.
The question is, and this is,
it really just comes down to the kind of analysis you need to perform as a team.
So, what is the change that I'm making?
Is it a fundamental change to the DAG that
actually changes the meaning of what we're trying to do?
Or are we adding at something that can be easily
reflected in the existing data pipeline that we've already designed?
So, if we go back to Airflow,
if we were to add say a marketing email send here,
the problem with that is that if we didn't update
our DAG or rerun the DAG to reflect that,
then that can cause issues for other people who might come by later and
think that for the last year
that this DAG has been running or whatever the time period is,
we sent all those emails.
But in fact, we haven't, right?
So, there are a couple of things you can do here.
You could design a new DAG.
Oftentimes that is the simpler solution.
The other option which you could explore would be to go in here,
go back to the DAGs page,
and you can actually clear the history of DAG runs.
So, one way to do that,
if I wanted to rerun lesson two demo one,
I could actually click in here and I can clear the history.
So, let me repeat that.
I went fast. So, on lesson two demo one,
looking at the recent tasks.
So, I'm going to click on the successful tasks.
This takes me to the task instances page,
which shows me all of the successful instances from lesson two demo one.
You can add or remove filters here.
In this particular case,
I actually going to remove the filter.
I just want all tasks related to lesson two demo one.
So, I'm going to do something interesting here.
I'm going to actually clear the history of these tasks.
So, I'm going to click apply. Oops, excuse me.
I'm going to hit, going to select all the tests on this page.
I'm going to hit with selected.
And then you see there's some options here.
I can actually change the state of these DAGS.
I'm going to clear them. So, Airflow is going to think that these tasks never run.
Okay. So you can see the tasks are back now,
but their state is none.
So, Airflow is actually going to try to rerun
these DAGs or rerun these tasks for this DAG.
Now here's the really important part to keep in consideration when you do this.
Airflow is going to rerun those tasks.
It has no concept of the data stores that you have outside of Airflow.
So, if rerunning a task is
destructive or rerunning a task triggers some kind of downstream action,
this can be really dangerous for
your internal usage of Airflow and for other data consumers.
So, it is possible to rerun a DAG or to clear the history of a DAG,
but you as the data engineer need
to intimately understand the repercussions of doing that.
So, that's where I bring up the idea that you
need to really weigh the benefits, the pros and cons,
between do I need a new DAG altogether,
where is design with this in mind?
Or do I need to actually go back and wipe history and try again?
So, I hope that answer helped.