In this lesson, we'll be covering
new concepts and expanding on a few we covered in lesson one.
Students will learn what data lineage is and why it's
critical to defining and maintaining your data pipelines.
Next, we'll go in depth on
data pipeline schedules and learn how to
leverage them to make our pipelines more manageable.
The handle on schedules will be ready to dive in on data partitioning
and see how partitioning can make our pipelines faster and more reliable.
We'll conclude this lesson with an overview of data quality, how it's defined,
and how we can build and test to our data pipelines to
ensure that our data pipelines are working as intended.