Pipeline is designed to work with partition data fail more gracefully.
Smaller datasets, smaller time periods,
and related concepts are easier to debug than big datasets,
large time periods, and unrelated concepts.
In Airflow, if you leverage the concepts of data
partitioning to help design the tasks in your DAG,
You'll find that debugging and rerunning failed tests will be much simpler.
Another great thing about Airflow is that if your data is partitioned appropriately,
your task will naturally have fewer dependencies on each other.
Because of this, Airflow will be able to parallelize
execution of your DAGs to produce your results even faster.
Another great thing about Airflow is that if your data is partitioned appropriately,
your task will naturally have fewer dependencies on each other.
Because of this, Airflow will be able to parallelize
execution of your DAGs to produce your results even faster.
This is an example from the previous demonstration.
You can see here that we
have both of these tasks and they're running state at the same time.
So, these two tasks are executing in parallel.