So, we're going to do one more demo.
For this demo, we're going to be taking a look at basically
how we can use Airflow tasks and features to test data quality with inner jags.
First, we're going to set an SLA on our bike share traffic calculation operator.
Then, we're going to add a data verification step after a load step from S3 Redshift.
Finally, we're going to add
a data verification step after we've calculated our output table.
So, we've got our dags off.
We're going to be turning on lesson two demo four in just a moment.
So, we're going to return to our demos.
We're going to open up demo four,
and then we're going to take a look through our code to see what's different here.
We can see we have a new function.
Check greater than zero.
This function isn't complete yet.
All we've done so far,
is we've actually selected account from a table.
That table comes in as a keyword argument.
So, we know we're going to need to provide context
to our Python operator that's actually running this data quality check.
So, let's go take a look at the operator that's actually going to run the check.
The first thing we have here is this check trips data Python operator.
We can see it's already partially configured.
It provides context, it calls the check greater than zero function,
and we've provided the perimeter the table name as trips.
So again, table name is trips and we're checking the trips table.
So, if I go back up, we can see that that parameter
is being pulled in off of the keyword arguments here.
So, we're going to get the table name to check from those keyword arguments.
Likewise, we're going to check the stations data in a similar fashion.
So, this is another new operator.
So here, we provided context,
and here we've given the name of the table as Stations. As you can see.
Final thing we need to do, is actually add these checks into our dag.
So, we're going to say after we've copied trips data,
we need to actually run the check trips task.
Sorry on line 72 it's actually check trips.
So, we're going to do check trips,
and then after we've done copy stations task,
we're going to run the check stations task.
However, our task isn't totally complete yet.
If we go back up to this function,
is not actually doing anything.
All it's doing is executing this function select a count of records from a table,
and then logging if it succeeded or not.
Well, we need to add some checks here.
So first, we need to make sure that records exist.
We also need to see that since records is going to be an array,
that we actually receive some rows to look at.
So, actually this should be if records is none or record zero.
The length of record zero is less than one.
Then, we're going to raise a value error.
Because no records present and destination table,
and this is going to be a format string.
So, we're going to raise an error because we want this task to fail.
If our check fails,
we want to raise a value error to denote the fact that the value is incorrect and wrong.
We're also going to log an error,
and we'll log more or less the same thing.
Essentially, we just want to say no markers are present,
and we want to make sure that's obvious so that in
the airflow logs we can see that something happened.
We're going to save our dag,
and then we're going to return to the dag menu and run this again.
Before we do that, I just want to show how to actually add an SLA.
SLA can be added to tasks and you do that by providing a time delta.
So, we have this Postgres operator here that creates the trips table.
This is pretty fast, so we're not going to look at this one.
We're going to look at the copy trips task.
This one can take a little while.
There could be a lot of data.
So, we want to set an SLA equal to a time delta for some amount of time.
So, in this case,
I don't have anything specific in mind,
but we could say let's say we wanted to complete within an hour.
Say hour is equal one.
If it needs to complete within a minute,
you could say minutes equal one,
or seconds equals 30 whatever the appropriate SLA is for your given task.
So, we've saved this.
We can go back to lesson two demo for in the UI.
We're going to look at the code. We want to make sure that it was parsed correctly.
So, we can see that our checks are now present,
and if we scroll down, we can see your copy trips task has an SLA.
So, I can return to our menu here and turn on and it's
still set to run monthly. All right.
So, jump into our graph view and we can see it's getting underway.
So, we're running our create trips tables and stations table. Those have run.
Now, we're going to start running the load trips and
load stations table which we've already seen before.
There was a completed. Now, we're actually going to run
our checks to make sure that data is present in those tables.
So, they're running, and they both completing successfully.
So, let's take a look at the logs and see what they got printed up.
So again, I clicked on a task and the graph view,
and then I'm going to click on view log to actually view log's going to scroll down.
We can see our log statement here.
Data quality on table trips check passed with nine million records,
almost 10 million records.
So, we can see that our data quality check passed.
If I went and deleted all the data from that table right now and re-run this task,
it would fail because there would be zero records present.