Data lineage describes the discrete steps involved in the movement,
creation, and calculation of a data set.
For example, in Lesson one,
we created a station traffic table which
contained a lifetime count of arrivals and departures at every bike share station.
We would be doing that in this redshift analysis step.
The diagram on the slide should look familiar.
We have a task for S3 to redshift,
and we have another task for redshift analysis.
The output of those two tests is the table below,
where we count the number of departures
and the number of arrivals for each of our bike stations.
So, you can see here we have station ID,
which is this bike station,
we have number of departures from that station,
as well as the number of arrivals from that station.
At some point, other engineers,
analysts, or other data consumers willing to make use of this data.
When these data consumers ask how the data was
calculated and what the source of the data for the calculation was,
we'll need to be able to tell them.
Being able to describe the data lineage
of our station traffic table will build confidence
in our users that are data pipeline is creating
meaningful results using the correct data sets.
If we can't answer questions and we're not sure what our data lineages,
it's less likely that our data consumers will trust our data sets and choose to use them.
So, again, if someone in our organization asked us how we calculated
the number of departures or the number of arrivals for say station 192,
we could actually point to this diagram up here and tell them
exactly what happened, step-by-step.
Here, we took data from the overall trips for all 2018,
and then we copy that CVS to redshift,
and then within redshift,
we performed analysis on that data set.
Another major benefit of servicing
the data lineage of your data sets is that it allows everyone in
the organization to agree on the definition of how a particular metric is calculated.
The more our bikeshare company grows,
the more people and divisions there will be that need to agree on key metrics.
If one person or group has one definition of a
metric and another person or group has a different definition,
we're going to be in a lot of trouble as a business.
Describing and servicing data lineage is one
of the key ways we can ensure that everyone in
the organization has access to and
understands where data originates and how it's calculated.
So, again, coming back to this table,
we are data engineers,
we designed our tasks.
If we have a business analyst or a data scientist who are partnered with,
who are our data customers,
they might ask us to prove that this number is correct.
In this particular case,
the calculation is not very involved,
but it's still important for us to be able to tell our data consumers exactly where
our data came from and how we calculated
it so that they trust that those numbers are correct.
Finally, as a data engineer,
data lineage helps us track down the route of errors when they occur.
If each step of the data movement and transformation process is well described,
we can easily find problems when they occur.
So, let's pretend again as
data engineers that we had a problem running this redshift analysis,
and it's entirely possible that in the last exercise while you're doing it,
you may have had an issue completing the lesson successfully the first time.
It's likely that maybe the table wasn't produced at all,
or maybe the table is produced with the wrong information.
In that scenario, we want to be able to know that the analysis failed.
In this particular case,
we might have not a number or NaNs in all of our rows,
and so this would be an indicator that something has failed.
There are additional steps we can add to our pipeline
to actually verify that we've run into these types of issues.
We're going to talk about that a little bit later in this lesson.
But for now, just seeing that the analysis step has failed
is already a really good start for us to find issues in our pipelines.
Returning to the last exercise of lesson one,
if our location traffic task had failed,
we can immediately identify the location of
that failure by using the graph view and airflow.
As you can see in this diagram,
location traffic, a circle with red to show that it failed.
Again, the location traffic failed here,
and some of you very well may have seen something similar in your first exercise.