Tracking data lineage in Airflow is simple.
As we've already seen in lesson one,
the Airflow UI parses our DAGs and surfaces a visualization of the graph.
So, as we've already covered,
we have create_table, load_from_S3_to_redshift,and then calculate_location_traffic.
Airflow keeps track of all runs of a particular DAG as tasks.
So again, we have our exercise six DAG down here,
and we have runs for each one each time that we've executed our DAG.
So, you can see here the dark green indicates
that the run is complete and that the task is complete.
So, the runs complete here in the circle and the square says the task is complete.
Airflow also shows us the rendered code for each task.
One thing to keep in mind,
Airflow keeps a record of historical DAGs and
task executions but it does not store the data from those historical runs.
Whatever the latest code is in your DAG definition
is what Airflow will render for you in the browser.
So, be careful in making assumptions about what was run historically.
So again, just to emphasize this,
if I went in and change the SQL on the slide, say,
I want to change the table name from station traffic to
just traffic or station traffic 2018.
If I did that and I updated my DAG,
Airflow is going to pick up that change and it's
going to render that for all historical DAG runs.
So, it's really important to understand that as you modify
DAGs that the code for historical runs will look different as well when you pull them up.
So, it does not keep a record of those historical code changes.
If you're going to make major changes to an existing DAG, say,
I wanted to completely change the analysis in this example,
it would be better to make an entirely new DAG
and turn this DAG off or give in an end date.
You should wait these decisions carefully with your team when they come up.
We're going to talk more about end dates very shortly.
Another nice thing about Airflow is that it's
a single visual point of reference for everyone on your team,
no matter how technical they are.
You can provide your data consumers access to the web UI,
so that they can open up View DAGs and their history.
Giving your data consumers the ability to view data lineage and your data pipelines,
goes a long way towards building trust in your data pipelines.