Okay. Now that you've seen data lineage and we've talked about data lineage,
we're going to go ahead and walk through demonstration.
So, we're actually going to just pick up where we left off on the previous demonstration.
So, I'm going to go to airflow,
I'm going to go back to lesson two demo one.
and I'm going to pull it up in the code.
So, when I close out of the solution for lesson six,
open demo one and then we're going to take a look at the code.
So, this code should look very familiar.
We have the function load trip data to redshift.
We have our DAG definition on line 24 to 27.
We have the create trips table, postgres operator.
We have our copy trips task,
Python operator, and finally we have the location traffic task.
Then we assign the create trips table to copy trips task.
All right. So we have three tasks here.
We create a table,
we copy the trips to that table and then finally we run a calculation.
So at this point, this is identical to the final exercise of less than one.
Before we move on, I want to actually run
this one more time just to get a history and listen to demo one.
So I'm going to turn on lesson two,
demo one and I made sure that lesson one solution six is turned off.
When it come over here and then I'm going to click to trigger the DAG.
I'm going to click "Okay".
As you can see, it's already started to schedule our tasks.
So we're going to wait a moment for this task to complete.
Now it's going to load the trips from S3 to redshift,
and you can see there's something very confusing about this.
Calculate location traffic isn't in the right place,
and if you look at our graph view,
we can see that it's actually not correctly connected to load trips from S3 to redshift.
Again, we can see here that load trips from S3 to redshift is not
directing itself to calculate location traffic. So that's an issue.
We may have some data left and redshift,
but because we're not using that data as a dependency for calculate location traffic,
we can't actually be sure that the right data was used, right?
If this run calculate location traffic
before we complete loading the trips from S3 to redshift,
what's in here anyway?
So, this is a bug in our DAG and it's something that we need to fix.
So, I'm going to return to the code and we can see that the issue
with the code here is that we never actually
assigned the location traffic task as a dependency.
Okay? So, I'm going to copy this and I'm going to correct this DAG.
So I'm going say copy trips task and I'm going to assign it.
Come back over here,
I'm going to go back to the DAG's page and we're going to run it one more time.
I show that once more and we can
see airflow is starting to actually run our task once again.
So I'm going to click in to lesson two,
demo one, and we can still see the DAG isn't rendering correctly.
So, airflow actually needs to finish running
the updated DAG steps to actually recognize the new ordering of the graph.
So when I click in here,
back to the graph view and we can see that this still looks the same as well.
So it can take airflow just a few moments to actually recognize the change.
So I'm going to refresh here a few times,
and then we can see that airflow actually recognizes the update to our DAG,
that the ordering is now correct.
Now, the purpose of this demonstration is to show you that you can
update the DAG and airflow will pick up those changes.
So, we were able to correct the mistake that we made in
this DAG by actually adding the ordering to the calculate location traffic table.
It's important to note that if we go back in history,
after this change has had a time to propagate through airflow.
So, if I look at the previous run,
we can see that it still shows us the correct layout for that particular run but
eventually this will actually correct itself
to look like it was a dependency of low trips from S3 to redshift.
So you can see,
we're looking at the old run and now airflow things that it ran,
calculate location traffic, afterload trips from S3 to redshift.
So, the reason I we're doing this demonstration is just to show you
that while airflow is a very powerful tool for tracking data lineage,
you need to be very careful with how you evolve your DAGs over time.
For example, if this wasn't a bug,
if this was actually in the steak,
or excuse me, if this wasn't a bug,
if this was actually a feature change to our DAG,
it would likely not be a good idea at all to update the DAG.
It would be a better idea to go back to the screen,
turn off lesson two,
demo one and create a second DAG with the change that we want it to reflect.
The reason for this is we don't want to confuse ourselves as history changes over time.