Well, we've already covered how to set a schedule on an airflow DAG in lesson one.
We didn't cover how airflow uses
this schedule interval to create historical DAG runs and backfill data.
Whenever the start of a DAG is in the past,
in a time difference between the start_date and
now includes more than one schedule intervals,
airflow will automatically schedule and execute
a DAG run to satisfy each one of those intervals.
Here's an example from lesson one, exercise three.
On the far left, you can see the first one of our DAG,
where are the start_date arrow is pointing.
So, here would be the start of the DAG.
So, the start_date here is now minus 60 days.
We have a monthly interval.
So, this would indicate that would be the start_date, okay?
The far left is your start_date.
On the far right, you can see
the most recent run of the DAG where the now arrow is pointing.
So, that would be here.
So, this would be the most recent run of our DAG.
Every column between start_date and now
represents an interval that a DAG run that airflow scheduled as backfill.
So, we can see the schedule interval as the period between two of these DAG runs.
So, each one of these columns represents a DAG run.
Basically, the time spacing between each one of these runs is the schedule_interval.
This feature is useful in almost all enterprise settings,
where companies have established years of
data that may need to be retroactively analyzed.
For example, we just recently talked about comparing
marketing data to trip data over a period of time.
We've used November as an example.
If I have five years of marketing data and I have five years of trip data,
even if I just set up an analysis and airflow,
I can actually set up my analysis to look at a day's worth of data at a time and use
airflow's backfill feature to make sure that I can have
a robust pipeline that will work a day at a time.
So, if my analysis fails,
say two years into my 10 years or five years worth of marketing data,
I don't lose all the data from the start up until that point.
So, this is a really useful feature and one that we can
exploit to really make our pipelines robust.
Finally, airflow pipelines can also have end_dates.
I mentioned this briefly in the past.
Perhaps, a dataset only spans a set period of
time or a project will be going end of life at some point.
Or perhaps, you've made substantial changes to
a DAG and you want to have a second reversion of it.
In both cases, you can use an end_date with
your pipeline to let airflow know to stop running the pipeline.
End_dates can also be useful when you want to perform
an overhaul or redesign of an existing pipeline.
Update the old pipeline with an end_date and then have
the new pipeline start on the end_date of the old pipeline.
So, for example, if this pipeline run from January to
April and then I wanted to replace this redshift analysis with a new one,
I might shift my start_date to the same day as the end_date of
the old pipeline and then not have an end_date so that it runs into the future.
In the next exercise, you'll have an opportunity to use an end_date.