Now that we know a little bit more about schedules and Airflow,
we're going to do a quick demo to add a schedule to our DAG.
So, the first thing I'm going to do,
I'm going to ask you guys to do the same thing
in the exercise when you perform this if you
were using the Airflow UI is to click this on button back to off.
We'll come back to lesson one demo to in a moment.
So, the first thing we're going to do,
is we're going to open exercise two.
So, I'm going to get back to the DAGs for the demos here.
So, I'm going to open demo two,
and all we're going to do,
so this should be pretty much exactly the same as the previous exercise.
The only thing we're going to do is add a schedule interval to the DAG,
starting on line 16.
So, I'm going to add a comma at the end of this start date,
and then I'm going to say schedule interval equal @monthly.
So, this tells Airflow,
hey I want you to run this DAG once a month.
I'm going to go ahead and save,
and that's really all there is to it.
So, the reason that we have this time delta of 30 days,
I'm actually going to make this 60 days just so it's a little more entertaining.
The only reason that we're setting it back 60 days is I want you guys to see
Airflow backfill for the last month. So, this says.
hey, the start date is right now minus 60 days.
So, it's going to be starting some point almost two months ago.
So, I'm going to refresh. I'm going
to make sure that my code was picked up by clicking on "Code View",
scroll down here, we can see that picked up my schedule interval at monthly,
you have a time delta of 60 days.
I'm going to go back to that front page,
and then I'm going to click the "On" button,
and then going to wait a few moments here and then refresh.
You'll notice that it's already run our task.
I didn't click the run button. I didn't click this.
The reason that it ran automatically is because we gave Airflow is schedule,
so it knows to run our DAGs when it has a schedule.
So you can see here it says @monthly.
Because their start date was 60 days ago,
Airflow thinks it's behind schedule,
that it needs to backfill to the previous month.
So, now if I refresh this you can see our task is successful,
so is our DAG run.