The only change you had to make was to go in here
and add schedule interval equal '@daily.'
So, now that you've done that,
you would see a similar result to what we saw here the difference being that,
because we have only a single day time delta,
you would still only see one run,
but your schedule here should say '@daily.'
Again, if you were interested to see the output,
you can click on the "Task" from here if you'd like,
you can click on "Hello World" task here,
and then click on "Log."
You can see that we printed "Hello world."
Alright. Again, I'm going to ask you guys if you can,
just make sure that you toggle your DAGS off when you're done using them.
In a normal airflow installation you would not toggle your DAGS off,
but I just want to make sure that for your exercises,
things are as simple as possible,
so that you're getting the most out of those exercises.