All right. Now, we're going to have another quick demo.
So I'm going to jump back over to my coding window here,
and I'm going to close out demo two and open demo three.
So now, that I have demo three open,
you can see there's a little bit more code here.
We have four functions defined,
a hello world function,
a current time function,
a working directory function,
and a complete function.
Now, there's no special meaning to any of these functions.
In fact, they're really just to show you how we can coordinate tasks before
we get into actually adding functionality
to these tasks that we'll be doing some heavy lifting with data.
So, the first thing we need to do is actually
define our tasks that utilize these functions.
So, we're going to follow this TODO here to create tasks
and operators and create one for current time.
So, we're going to current_time_task equal to PythonOperator. All right.
We're going to give this a task_ID equal to current time.
We're going to give it a python_callable.
In this case, it's going to be current_time,
and then we're going to set it equal to this DAG.
We're going to repeat this for working directory.
So, we're going to, again, define the task as a PythonOperator.
The task_id equal to working_dir.
We're going to give it a python_callable.
Again, this one's going to reference the working_dir function on line 17.
Then finally, assign as a DAG,
and we have one final task that we need to define which is going to be the complete task.
Okay? So, we're going to say PythonOperator,
task _id equal complete task.
Sorry. We'll be consistent here and call it complete.
Then, we're going to say python_callable equal complete on line,
which is our function defined in line 21.
Then, we're going to set it equal to that DAG.
So now, we have four tasks defined.
You have hello world task on line 30.
We have current_time_task on line 36,
and we have the working_dir_task on 41,
and on line 46, the complete_task.
Now, we need to define a task such that our graph looks like the following.
So, to do that,
we need to set up the task ordering in Airflow.
So, we're going to start with hello_world_task.
We can see from this graph that we've drawn the code here.
The hello_world_task points to current_time task.
So, we're going to say hello_world_task depends on- excuse me,
current_time_task depends on hello_world_task.
So, we're going to set those Chevron's such that hello_world_task happens first.
Likewise, working_dir_task comes first.
So, over here, we're going to say hello_world_ task,
depends on working_dir _task her.
The final thing we need to do here,
this is actually a typo in my demo, complete_task.
The final thing we need to say is that
once current_time_task and working_dir_task have been completed,
we want to execute complete_task through as a current time task, complete task.
Then we're going to say, working_dir_task
must be completed before complete tasks can run.
So now, I'm going to save this,
and we're going to go take advantage of the Airflow UI to see if we got this right.
If we didn't, we can come back and fix it.
So, I'm going to refresh the page.
I'm going to click on the code here for lesson- or excuse me,
for demo three. We're going to scroll down.
We can see our four functions.
We can see the three operators that we defined,
and then we can see our task ordering,
hello_world_task, and current_time task, and so on so forth.
So, I'm going to scroll back to the top,
and then I'm going to go to this graph view on the upper left-hand corner.
This actually shows us that what we described in code is correct.
I can zoom in here to make this a little bit easier to see. Then I'm going to click that.
You see I have a hello_world_task pointing to a working_dir_ task,
and then hello_world pointing on current_time_task.
These two tasks must be completed before the complete_task runs.
So, let's see this in action.
I'm going to go back to- or actually,
I'm not going to leave this page.
I'm going to stay on this page, and I can toggle this on here by clicking this button.
So, this DAG is now on,
and I can click on the Tree View,
and I can wait here in a few moments for Airflow to actually schedule and run our task.
I can go ahead and refresh.
Hopefully, the Airflow schedulers picked it up,
and you can see that it has.
So, we've actually already run the hello_world_task.
If I refresh again,
we can watch it progress,
and this is on an hourly schedule.
You can see this up here.
I have it set to an hourly schedule so it's going to run a few times.
We've now run the working directory tasks and the current_time_task,
and if I refresh again,
we can see that our first DAG is totally complete.
We can also see that future DAGs are now running.
Airflow is in the process of back filling.
We'll talk more about this in lesson two,
but I thought it would be fun to show it to you now.
So, I'll go back to the Graph View.
You can actually see an example of various runs.
So, we can see all the various runs that have occurred.
Moving forward in time,
I'm going to click the first one and then I'm going to click Go.
So, you can see by the dark green color here that everything has executed.
I can click into any of these tasks,
and I can see the logs that were emitted,
just like we did for the hello_world_task.
So, if I scroll down here,
this task was to print the working directory,
and you can see that it did just that,
printed user local Airflow.