Now, I'm going to walk through a demonstration of how to configure and
connect to Amazon key-value store, S3. All right.
So we're going to open up the Airflow UI,
and when we turn off demo 3,
and then we're going to open up demo 4.
So you can see the instructions that we're going to go through here.
We're going to create a variable,
and we're going to create a connection.
We'll start by defining that variable.
So we can define variables in the Airflow UI for our DAGs.
To do that, you're going to click on the Admin button at the very top of the screen,
then you're going to go to the Variables menu option,
click on that, and it's going to bring you to the screen.
From here, there's nothing in the list because we haven't created any variables yet.
So we're going to click the Create button.
Airflow gives you a lot of space to put in a value here because
your value might be a large amount of JSON or XML,
it could be an SSH key although you shouldn't put
SSH keys and values because those are secure.
So don't do that, but it might be some large amount of text.
In our case, it's not going to be something significant.
We're going to create a bucket key.
So we're going to call the key s3_bucket,
and then we're going to set the value to what we have in the instructions here.
So in Step 3, we walked through the examples here,
go to admin Variables, click Create,
and then we're going to set the s3_bucket value to udac-data-pipelines.
Paste that in, and then I'm simply going to click the Save button.
So it takes you back to the Variables page,
and you can see here key and value.
All right. Next, we're going to create a connection to Amazon.
So we're going to go to Connections under the Admin menu.
So we clicked on Admin,
went to Connections, and then in here,
there are a lot of default connections.
You can safely ignore all of this.
These aren't connected talk to any real data stores.
So we're going to click on the Create button again on this tab here,
and then you're going to be greeted with a number of
options to actually create a connection.
In this particular case,
we're going to create a connection ID called aws_credentials,
and then we're going to select a connection type called Amazon Web Services.
So there are a number of options on this menu.
It can be really overwhelming when you're first getting used to using
Airflow to look at this menu and know where to put information.
In this course, we're going to try and make it as obvious and clear as possible,
and then walk through these examples where things go.
To start, we're to fill in a login.
So the login for Amazon Web Services is
going to be the IM credentials that we're going to be using throughout this class.
So this is going to be your access key ID.
Again, that's your access key ID.
So in this case, I'm going to pre-populate it,
and then for the password,
that's going to be your secret key ID.
So I'm going to use my password manager here to get that.
So grab that password.
So now my password is entered into that field.
I'm just going to go ahead and click Save.
So now we can see that record was successfully created,
I'm going to double check in this list to see that it's present.
So we can see here, we have aws_credentials,
and we can see that airflow has encrypted our credentials.
So now, I'm going to go back and double-check,
and we can see that we follow the directions here.
So we created our Admin Connections,
we filled in our aws_credentials, and we saved.
So the DAG is actually already ready to go.
I've already pre-populated it with a function that
will list all of the values in an s3_bucket.
So you don't actually have to do any work here.
All you got to do is go out to Airflow, click on DAGs,
and then turn on lesson 4,
and refresh, then once you've turned it on,
we're going to click the Play button and trigger it.
I don't have this one on a schedule.
Go ahead and click Play,
and we're going to wait for it to run.
So this may take a few moments.
Unlike the previous demonstrations,
there is a little bit of work going on behind the scenes here. So now it's done.
So I'm going to click in the lesson 1 demo 4,
and then I'm going to click on the actual task to see if it did what I asked it to do,
which if we go back here,
you can see we're listing the key.
So it's getting an S3_hook,
it's using that variable that we defined.
So before we look at the logs, I want to walk through this.
You can see that we're using the S3_hook.
So this is going to talk to Amazon's S3.
It's using the AWS connection ID, aws_credentials.
Remember, this was the name that we gave to the credentials that we were using.
Once we've gotten that hook,
we can actually use it to list the keys in a particular s3_bucket.
Instead of hard coding the s3_bucket into my Airflow DAG,
I've actually told it to use an airflow variable,
and you can see that I've imported that on Line 5,
we have airflow variable.
I've imported the airflow variable and ask it to give me the name of the s3_bucket.
So what's nice about this is whether
it's this example or something else in the real-world,
chances are as a data engineer,
configuration within your data engineering environment
needs to change, whether that's credentials,
or its locations of things with an S3,
or names of database tables, things like that.
You can actually use airflow variables to make managing those much simpler.
Finally, all we're going to do is list all the keys in that bucket.
So let's go back, and let's actually view the logs from our list_keys function.
So let me close out of this and just get into it one more time.
So again, we're in the Tree View for our DAG lesson 1 demo 4,
we're going to click on Our Task,
and then click View Log.
We're going to scroll down,
and then you can see here listing keys from udac-data-pipelines,
and you can see a whole bunch of stuff.
We're actually going to be using these datasets throughout the rest of the course.
So you're getting a preview of the data that you're going to be working with,
and you can see everything in this s3_bucket,
and so we did all of that again by using connections and variables.