What is a data pipeline?
Before we dive into the definition of a data pipeline,
let's discuss a few examples of data pipelines you may have encountered.
Chances are, you've already interacted with
the output of a data pipeline multiple times today.
Open your email inbox and have a look at a few of our marketing emails.
A lot of these emails are probably personalized for you directly,
and were triggered after a data pipeline executed.
Maybe you used a rideshare app like Lyft or Uber,
where you were offered real-time pricing.
Companies commonly use data pipelines to
orchestrate the analysis that determines pricing.
Perhaps you were shopping online,
left without purchasing anything,
and then suddenly saw advertisements for the items you were shopping for on our websites.
At its most basic definition,
a data pipeline describes encode a series of sequential data processing steps.
Depending on the data requirements for each step,
some steps may occur in parallel.
Data pipelines also typically occur on a schedule.
That schedule could be once an hour,
once a day, every minute, or once a year.
The cadence largely depends on how frequently data is delivered,
and how often data consumers need new insights.
Schedules are the most common mechanisms of triggering an execution of a data pipeline,
external triggers and events can also be used to execute data pipelines.
Extract, transform and load, or extract, load,
and transform, are common patterns found in data pipelines,
but not strictly required.
Some data pipelines perform only a subset of ETL or ELT.
Let's return to one of our earlier examples,
and see how a company might use a data pipeline to accomplish a goal.
Let's pretend that we work in a Bikeshare company,
and want to figure out where our busiest locations are.
We might use this data to determine where to build additional locations,
or simply to add more bikes.
A data pipeline to accomplish this task would likely
first load application event data from a source such as S3 or kafka.
Second, we might take that data and then
load it into an analytic warehouse such as RedShift.
Then third, perform data transformations that identify high-traffic bike docks.