So, now that we've talked about data pipelines and data validation,
I want to talk a little bit about directed acyclic graphs.
The reason that we're talking about directed acyclic graphs or DAGs is
because the data pipelines are well-expressed as directed acyclic graphs.
Before we dig into why they're such a good fit,
let's quickly review what a DAG is.
As engineers, we use graphs to describe
concepts and relationships that exist between them.
Graphs are everywhere in software engineering,
and there are powerful concept and modeling complex systems.
Graphs describe entities and the relationships that exist between them.
Famously, Facebook uses the concept of
a graph to model their users as nodes and their relationships,
otherwise known as edges,
to others as friends and family.
So, in this image here,
you can see just a real quick example of people and the relationships between them.
This is just basically a snapshot of visualization of what a graph might look like.
Another example that I like are airlines.
Airlines use graphs to model the routes.
Airports can be modeled as nodes,
which have edges to each other in the form of flight paths.
So, there's a lot going on in this image as you can see there's a lot of lines here.
If we were able to actually see something,
you might see Chicago here and then a bunch of lines going out from
Chicago to other airports like San Francisco,
New York City, et cetera.
DAGs or directed acyclic graphs are a special subset of graphs in which
the edges between nodes have a specific direction and no cycles exist.
When we say no cycles exist,
what we mean is the nodes can't create a path back to themselves.
Looking at the graph,
we can say that A has a relationship to B,
but B does not have relationship back to A.
This what we mean when we say that this is a directed graph and we can say the same thing
between about the edges or the relationships between all the nodes in this graph.
We denote that relationship and the direction of that relationship with this arrow.
So, you can see we have an arrow here saying that A
has a relationship to B. Additionally,
if we look at this graph, we can see that no cycles exist.
Once a node has been visited,
there's a clear progression to next set of nodes.
So, once we've gone from A to B for example,
there is no path that takes me back to A.
So, if there was a path that took me back to A,
I'd have a cycle in my graph.
DAGs are a natural fit for representing data pipelines.
If we consider the steps of a traditional ETL process for example,
we will see that the process typically involves a series of discrete steps.
First, we extract data and that's what we're going to represent with this E. Then,
once extraction's complete, we're going to transform it.
Finally, we load the transformed data somewhere.
Each step depends on the last.
To transform the data,
we must first extract it.
If extraction fails, then there is no data to transform.
Likewise, if we fail to transform the data,
there is no data to actually load.
Given that we consider each step in the ETL process as a node in
our graph and the completion of that step as
the relationship or edge between these nodes.