All right. So, let's visualize our Bikeshare analysis process from earlier as a DAG.
First, we're going to extract the data from S3 and load the data from S3 into Redshift.
So, I've represented that process as this light blue circle here, S3 to Redshift.
Then, we're going to perform analysis in Redshift using SQL.
Finally, we might deliver our data to some destination server.
So, these are three discrete steps,
which we've represented here with the node,
we have an edge or relationship to another node.
So, as time goes on,
it's not uncommon to need to modify or add new data sources to our data pipelines.
Let's say we decide to integrate additional data about traffic from the city.
We might hypothesize that high traffic areas
are also places where we would like to place Bikeshare locations.
You now want to incorporate that information into your Redshift analysis.
To access this data,
you will need to extract the data from
the city's API and load it into a table and Redshift for analysis.
The step will need to be completed before we perform Redshift analysis.
So, in this diagram,
you can see here we've added another task and another edge to a Redshift analysis,
and this task is HTTP to Redshift.
So, we can just imagine here that we're talking to
the city's data API to get traffic information and then loading it to Redshift.