So now that we're familiar with data pipelines and DAGs,
I'd like to introduce Apache airflow.
Airflow is an open source tool which marries the concepts we've been talking
about into an easy to use and intuitive framework.
So on the screen right now,
you can see a sample of the airflow user interface.
We're going to be talking more about this shortly,
but I just want to give you a bit of a taste of what you're about to see.
So airflow is created at Airbnb with the goal of
organizing their substantial and complicated data pipeline infrastructure,
into one tool that can run in mission critical environments.
Another goal was making sure that teams could understand
at a glance how their pipelines were triggered or scheduled,
and how all of the steps and their DAGs fit together.
Since 2015, airflow has experienced explosive growth,
has been adopted by data engineering teams at some of the biggest names in the industry.
What makes airflow so popular is that it makes writing
and deploying data pipelines simpler than ever before.
Airflow DAGs are written in Python.
A language that is friendly for developers and
used widely by data engineers and their tools.
Additionally, airflow comes out of the box with
integrations for widely used tools like Redshift,
S3, Spark and more.
But integration doesn't exist for a tool you want to work with,
airflow has a simple interface for building
that integration and sharing it with other developers.
Perhaps best of all, airflow makes visualizing your DAGs easier than ever before.
All a developer has to do to create
a visual representation of their DAG is to code it in Python,
and then pull it up in the Airflow UI.
The Airflow UI automatically transforms a DAG you've
written in Python into a DAG visualization.
Complete with the schedule, execution diagrams,
log output, as well as a host of other great features which we're going to cover.
So real quick on this slide,
you can see an example of a DAG over here.
You can see the relationships.
You can see the nodes.
Although it's a little bit blocked here,
on the screenshot you can even see all of the executions.
Each one of these columns is an execution for a particular date.
Don't worry if this isn't perfectly clear right now,
we're going to spend more time in this UI, and it'll get more familiar.