So, we're looking at right now is the solution to
the first task which looks very similar to the demonstration I gave you.
So, we need to define a function Hello World,
and if he didn't say Hello World,
that's totally fine, you can print whatever you want.
The second part of it was to add a greet task which is line 16 to 20.
Here, you can call the task ID anything you want as long
as it's somewhat descriptive of what the task is performing.
We provided the Hello World callable.
This Hello World callable is related to the function we defined on line eight.
So, notice here on line 18,
I didn't write Hello World function call.
I'm not calling the function.
I'm actually passing that function to the Python operator so that when it executes,
it knows what to execute.
Finally, we assigned the DAG to the DAG field of our Python operator,
so the operator knows what DAG it belongs to.
All right. Again, we saw already how we ran this through the Airflow UI.
So, if it was successful,
you would see a green success and a green run over here as well.
I'm going to demonstrate a failure state in the near future here,
but if you had any issues,
you would see a red failed bulb over here and over here in this column.