So, now, we're going to move into actually creating a DAG.
Creating a DAG in Airflow,
as we already saw in the previous example,
is as simple as importing the class from the Airflow module and instantiating it.
All you need to get going is a name for your DAG and a description of what it does.
You'll also need to specify when Airflow should
begin executing a DAG by giving it a start date.
For some DAGs, you may want the start date to be today.
For others though, you may want to set this time in the past.
This feature is useful if you have older datasets
that you want to process in pieces rather than all at once.
We'll cover this in detail later in the course,
but for now, you just need to know this is a very useful feature.
Finally, most DAGs run on a scheduled basis.
You define a schedule for your DAG by giving it a schedule interval.
In this example, you can see that we've
given it a daily interval so this DAG should run once a day.
We'll talk a little bit about this syntax here in a moment.
Operators are the building blocks of DAGs.
They define the actual work what a DAG will perform.
Operators are abstracted nature and need to be
parameterized in your pipeline definition to actually be used.
So, we're parameterizing it here.
Once you've parameterized and instantiated an operator for use in your DAG,
it is referred to as a task.
When I said that you've parameterized an operator,
I mean that we provided the Python operator or
function the parameters it needs to function.
So, we have three parameters here that paramaterize our Python operator,
we have the task_id, python_callable, and a DAG.
In this example, we define a task built on
the Python operator which executes the function Hello World.
So, this should look very familiar to you from the previous demo.
So, that explains all the components that we've used so far.
Airflow defines a handful of other special schedule strings once,
hourly, daily, weekly, and so on and so forth.
You can also specify schedules using cron format.
If you set your schedule to none,
the Python value none,
the scheduler will only run the DAG when you initiate a run through the UI.
If you omit a schedule altogether,
your DAG will default to running once a day.
Again, if you don't specify a schedule by default,
it will run once a day from the start date.
If your start date is in the past,
Airflow run your DAG as many times as there are
schedule intervals between that start date and the current date.
Unless you specify an optional end date,
Airflow will continue to run your DAG until you disable or delete the DAG.
It's important to note that the Airflow scheduler will do
its best to run DAGs in our tasks as soon as it can.
However, depending on how busy your Airflow workers are,
that may not be right away.
If your Airflow workers have more work than they can
handle or a task is taking a long time,
new work will have to wait for older work to finish.
It's important to be mindful of this as you pick how
frequently your DAG and your task should run.