Airflow provides a number of context variables specific to
the execution of a given DAG and a task at runtime.
These context variables like execution date are often useful in
the process of accessing or segmenting data before processing.
This looks very similar to our hello world function that we saw earlier.
We have a function defined here called hello_date.
Hello is a little bit different.
We have *args, and **kwargs, and we're printing,
we're using a Python 3 formatted string here to print hello,
and then referencing keyword arguments execution_date.
So, what this is doing is it's trying to get the named variable,
execution_date are the keyword arguments. Where's that coming from?
We don't really have it in here anywhere.
Well, it's coming from context.
So, we've changed our PythonOperator to provide_context equal True.
in doing that, Airflow is automatically
going to pass through a number of runtime variables
to the application such that you can
access them in your Python function or in other operators.
So, see what that would look like.
So, before we do the demo,
and we come back here.
Turn off lesson1.demo4, and we're going to jump into lesson5.
So, we're going to go demo5, and we're going to open that up.
So, we're going to see here that we aren't providing context yet.
On line 25, 29 we have a PythonOperator called list_task,
which we need to pass in contexts too.
So, if we come over here or say provide_context equal True.
So, this means that PythonOperator will get
the runtime context that it needs
to actually print out any of the variables that we might be interested in.
Now, before we continue,
I want to show you a list of the variables that are available to Airflow.
So, I'm going to go back here,
and open a new tab,
and I'm going to open up the Airflow documentation.
Now, I've included this list in your example as well.
So, don't worry about having to go find this documentation through Google or other means.
Just go to the demo exercise,
and when you're doing the exercise like this,
just grab this link,
go to your browser, and you can take a look at what's in here.
So, we have all these variables to find here; ds, prev_ds.
I'm not going to go through all of these,
it's a pretty extensive list.
But I do want to talk about the one that we've already talked
about a little bit in our example, which was execution_date.
We can see here what execution_date is,
is a datetime.datetime object.
So, this is going to tell us essentially what is
the date on which this task is actually executing.
Now, this is really useful if you're backfilling.
Let's say you're running a DAG that was scheduled for 2013,
and it's 2019 or 2020 or whenever it is today,
Airflow is going to tell the DAG when it runs when it was intended to be run.
This is very useful for backfilling in segmenting data.
We're going to talk more about segmenting data later.
But for now, I want you guys just to focus on looking at the kinds
of variables that are going to be provided to you through context.
So, now that we're going to go back to our DAG,
and I think real quick before we go,
I'm going to print off this ds variable in my demonstration.
So, this is a nice simple one.
It's just going to print the execution date as a string in the format YYYY-MM-DD.
So, again, I don't care about these double brackets on either side.
Their variable name is the same inquiries,
so we want the ds.
I'm going to take that, I'm going to go back here.
So, I have this log_details function and I'm saying,
"I need the logs and details of the run."
Well, to do that.
I need to get rid of this pass because we want to actually do something.
Just like in the first exercise,
I'm going to do a logging.info statement here.
Now, the big difference here is,
I'm going to use a Python 3 format string.
Okay. But I haven't put anything in the string yet.
Let's say, My execution date is",
and then I'm going to put in the brackets that Python knows to render this.
I'm going to go in here, I'm going to say kwargs,
which is a list of keyword arguments or dictionary keyword arguments.
I'm going to ask it to print out ds.
Okay? That's all there is to it.
So, now, I have access to the date stamp.
I can add another one here too for execution date while in here.
So, I copied that line.
I'm going to update this and say, execution_date.
Just make sure I got that right, execution_date.
Yeah. Then, I'm going to go back to Airflow.
So, I'm going to close this tab,
make sure I say my code. All right.
So, he saved and then I go back to the Airflow UI.
I'm going to turn on lesson1.demo5 and see what happens.
So, let's refresh. So, we have a task in the queued state,
so that hasn't started running yet.
Just a reminder while we're waiting here,
workers pickup tasks from the queue.
So, the scheduler has placed this task into the queue,
but the worker hadn't yet picked it up to run.
We can see that our DAG is in the running state.
Going to go ahead and refresh,
and our task has already completed.
So, we're going to go ahead and go into demo5.
I'm going to click on the log_details task,
and then we're going to check the logs.
Scroll down and we can see that it
printed it's execution date twice in different formats.
This is the ds format,
where it just gives us the year, month, and day,
and this is is the datetime format execution date,
2019-02-05, and then no hours,
minutes, seconds, or micro seconds.