So, now we're going to talk about what Airflow is actually made up of operationally.
Airflow consists of five runtime components.
We're going to give you an environment where
these pieces are already configured in this class,
whether you're using docker compose or you're using cocoa.
But it's still important to understand what they are and how they work.
The scheduler is responsible for tracking the progress of
DAGS and their tasks as well as ensuring that they are triggered properly.
A Queue holds the state of running DAGS and tasks.
Airflow worker processes take data off the queue and actually
execute the integral individual tasks and your DAG.
A database, stores your credentials,
configuration, connections, and history,
what we refer to this as metadata.
And finally the web server is the web interface that we've been interacting with so far.
One thing I want to mention real quick.
Airflow itself is not a data processing framework,
in Airflow you don't pass data in memory between steps in your DAG.
Instead, you're going to use Airflow to coordinate the movement of
data between other data storage and data processing tools.
If we just stop here for just a moment,
you'll notice that we do have a database here but it's strictly a metadata database.
We don't store actual data related to our datasets in this database or in this queue.
These workers when they execute,
will work with Redshift,
Spark, other types of systems that are not actually on this diagram.
So just to clarify, we're not going to pass data between steps or tasks and we will
not typically run heavy processing workloads on Airflow.
Reason for this is that Airflow workers often have less memory and processing
power individually and some dataframe works offer an aggregate.
Tools like Spark or able to expose the computing power of many machines all at once.
Whereas with Airflow you will always be limited to
the processing power of a single machine.
So if this worker were one machine,
would only have access to the memory and CPU of just that machine.
This is why Airflow developers prefer to use Airflow to trigger
heavy processing steps in
analytic warehouses like Redshift or dataframe works like spark.
Instead of within Airflow itself.
Airflow can be thought of as a partner to those dataframe
works or data warehouses but not as a replacement.
Airflow is designed to codify the definition and execution of data pipelines.
Airflow tracks the status and progression of
all DAGS in its system as well as the steps within those DAGS.
Because Airflow understands the dependencies in your DAG,
the scheduler will only place work that can be performed
and have had their dependency is satisfied into the queue.
In this example, our DAG has been triggered by a schedule.
You can see in the diagram this clock icon indicates the scheduler has
recognized that a DAG run must occur due to the time of day.
Once the scheduler has decided to execute a DAG,
it analyzes the various tasks that make up the DAG,
and finds all tasks that have no dependencies.
This is first task that it's going to choose to run.
So in this example, we can see our old HTTP to Redshift and S3 Redshift tests.
They have no arrows pointing into them.
Therefore they have no dependencies,
so they can be run first.
The scheduler then places those tasks in the queue,
so that workers will pick up those tasks for execution. So we stopped here.
I'm going to move onto the next slide now.
So as workers in the queue,
workers pick up the tasks and execute them.
When the worker completes a task,
the status is recorded by the scheduler.
So you can see here this actually
correlates really nicely with the question that we were just talking about,
which is what do the workers actually do?
Again the worker will take the work off of the queue,
the task off of the queue and actually execute them.
The scheduler repeats the following steps until all steps in
the DAG have completed successfully or Intel DAG fails.
So, in the previous steps we talked about completing
the HTTP to Redshift and S3 to Redshift tasks.
Now those are complete the dependencies to our Redshift analysis task.
Excuse me, our Redshift analysis task are complete.
So the Airflow scheduler is now going to actually execute the Redshift analysis task.
Once all tasks and the DAG have been completed,
the DAG run is complete.
You can use the Airflow UI to track the progression
of any DAG run and see that it has succeeded.
So this is what we'd see if we had multiple tasks in Airflow UI.
The dark green denotes that it was completed successfully.