It's important to be aware that subDAGs do have
a number of downsides in addition to their upsides.
First, subDAGs limit your visibility within the Airflow UI.
When we replace repeated tasks with the subDAG,
it's not immediately obvious what steps are happening within the subDAG.
As you can see here,
we have the create_trips_table and a create_stations_table,
the load, the check,
and it's very clear what's happening.
If I was a user who had never seen this DAG before and open up the Airflow UI,
I'd have a pretty good idea of what was happening by looking at these steps.
As you can see here, our code may have gotten simpler by adding
a subDAG but it's a lot less clear what the subDAGs themselves are doing.
You'd have to actually click on the trips_subDAG or
the stations_subDAG to actually see the steps that make up that DAG.
The key takeaway here is that you should apply subDAGs only
when you think you have more than one use case in your code already.
If you think you might have a use case in the future,
the additional complexity and reduced usability in
the UI is likely not worth the trade off until the time actually comes.
SubDAGs are easy to abuse,
so think twice before using them.
Second, subDAGs are not properly scoped are often
more difficult to understand than the code they originally replaced.
Let's pretend in the previous example we had simply included
the table calculations step of our DAG into the subDAG as well.
So, here, it's no longer just S3ToRedShiftSubDAG, it's now S3ToRedShiftCalculateSubDAG.
Again, we have calculate added in.
At this point, we've given up a lot of visibility into how our DAG works.
We just have this one giant box for both of our DAGs.
What does the subDAG calculating anyway?
How is it applying the calculation in a title?
What calculation is it even using?
Though it may sound appealing to obstract away the entirety of our data pipeline,
we've actually obfuscated the purpose of the pipeline
and made it much more difficult to understand what's going on.
Third, subDAGs tend to encourage premature optimization.
Make sure you're creating a subDAG obstraction that is
justified by an opportunity for reuse or clarity.
As Donald Knuth once said,
"Premature optimization is the root of all evil."
Although those quote may be a bit dramatic,
it is fun and makes an excellent point about
how good intentions can lead to bad outcomes as far as obstractions go.
To put that quote in context,
Donald Knuth was pointing out that engineers often focus on
finding efficiencies and noncritical parts of the programs.
He prefaces this quote by saying,
"These attempts at efficiency actually have
a strong negative impact when debugging and maintenance are considered."
So, we've all seen this affecting code before.
SubDAGs are a powerful tool but they're ripe for abuse if used incorrectly.
Make sure you're creating a subDAG obstraction that is
justified by an opportunity for reuse or clarity.
To finish out that quote from Donald Knuth, he also notes that,
we should not forget about small efficiencies,
say, 97 percent of the time.
That we should never pass up that opportunity in that critical three percent.
So, the reason I brought that up is it's not so
much that the ratio matters 97 percent versus three percent,
but that even though subDAGs can be difficult to use,
they are very important to use when the time is appropriate.
You'll develop a sense for this as you go through and
you'll see an example of it in the coming demonstration.