In this demo, we're going to create a DAG that uses a subDAG.
You'll see how to populate a subDAG and instantiate it in your own DAGs.
So, we're going to return to the homepage of Airflow,
and then we're going to jump back to the code.
First thing I'm going to do is I'm going to open the folder lesson3.demo3.
I just want to stop for a moment and point out that in your exercise you will have
an exercise3 folder, not an exercise3.py.
So, expect to see a folder called exercise3.
Then this folder, you're going to see two files: dag.py and subdag.py.
Let's first look at our DAG.
So, you'll see this DAG looks fairly standard so far.
We have a DAG definition.
But almost immediately, you'll see that we have something called a SubDagOperator,
which is something that we haven't seen before.
I'm going to show you how we created the subDAG in a moment,
but I first wanted to show you how it gets used in the DAG.
So, the first thing to point out here is that we've imported the SubDagOperator.
You can see this on line five.
So, a SubDagOperator is much like other operators we've talked about in this class,
such as PostgresOperator or Python operator,
but the important thing to keep in mind is that
the SubDagOperator is actually calling a Python factory function.
In the case of line 22,
it's calling the get_s3_to_redshift_dag function to return a DAG.
So, this operator is actually executing an entire DAG.
We'll get into these arguments here in just a moment.
For now, we can just ignore them.
Let's go take a look at our subDAG.
So, again, lesson3.demo3, we're going to open subdag.py.
If this was your exercise,
you would open lesson3.exercise3, subdag.py.
In here, you're going to see a number of things to find
that look somewhat familiar once we finish the demonstration.
At this point, we've only defined a function that takes a number of arguments.
This function get_s3_to_redshift_dag and returns it.
So, you can see we have another DAG defined in here.
So, even though this is a function,
it is actually defining and returning a DAG.
It's also worth mentioning,
and this is very important that we have
the DAG name defined as the parent_dag_name.task_id.
You must name your subDAGs following this pattern.
Airflow will actually throw an error if you don't follow this pattern.
So, again, the name of your subDAGs must always be the name of
the parent DAG dot the name of the new task ID.
All right. So, now that we've done that,
we're going to actually start to combine the functionality from our DAG into the subDAG.
So, I'm going to open,
I'm going to do a split window here.
I'm going to open this DAG below so we can start moving the code around.
So, on the top window here where I'm moving the cursor,
this is our subDAG,
and you can see that on the middle section here it says dags/lesson3/demo3/subdag.py.
The bottom code, this is our Dag.
We want to move some of the code from the this DAG into our subDAG.
So, we're going to move down here,
and we're going to move the create_table code into our subDAG.
So, I'm going to just grab this,
copy and create code,
and I'm going to paste it in.
Now, we're not done quite yet because this is specific,
this code is specifically formatted for the trips_table.
The whole point of a subDAG is that it's supposed to be reusable.
So, if we wrote a subDAG that just works on trips_table,
that really wouldn't be very useful.
So, the first thing we need to do is go back and look at our arguments.
Here, we'll notice that we have a table, we have our bucket,
key, all of the arguments that we actually
need to instantiate the operators this task uses.
So, I'm going to scroll down here.
We're going to go ahead and give this task_id,
we're going to turn this into a formatter.
So, we're going to use Python formatting to say, create_table argument table.
The DAG, we want that to be the DAG that we defined within our subDAG on line 25.
Next, we need to pass in a Postgres connection ID,
but we can't be sure that it's going to be redshift.
Maybe we want to talk to a different cluster
or different database altogether and a subDAG.
We can't make those kinds of assumptions.
So, we need to go up here and grab
the redshift connection ID variable and fill it in for our Postgres connection ID.
Finally and importantly, we don't know what SQL we need to execute.
Who knows what the create_trips SQL might look like.
So, to do that,
we need to grab this create SQL statement,
which we're going to pass in,
and we're going to execute that.
All right. So, now our create_trips_table,
and it really shouldn't have the name trips in it anymore.
So, we call this create_table.
Our create_table task in our subDAG has been fully configured.
Next, we need to look at our copy_trips_task and make this generic.
So, the first thing we're going to do is remove
this trips variable or trips name
from our variable name because now we just want a generic copy task.
Unlike in the previous example,
we're going to use a formatting string and say, load_table from s3_to_redshift.
Here, we're going to delete the trips_table because
the table could be anything now that it's a subDAG that's reusable,
and then we're going to replace the redshift_conn_id with redshift_conn_id.
Again, these variables are coming from our function up here.
Next, we need to fill in the s3 bucket and key and the aws_credentials_id.
So here, we can no longer assume that the aws_credentials is aws_credentials,
so we're going to use our variable aws_credentials_id.
We're going to replace this specific bucket name with
a variable name because the user may want to specify a different bucket.
Finally, it will replace the key with
a different key because the user may want to specify a different key.
Now, at this point, we've defined our S3ToRedshiftOperator in a reusable fashion.
Our subDAG is almost ready to go except we're missing one thing.
We need to define ordering of our tasks.
The create_task must occur before the copy_task.
So, you can see here, I'm going to delete these TO DO's since we've done it.
You can see here we have create_table, we have copy_task.
So, we want to make sure that the create_table occurs before the copy_task.
Now that we've done that, we can actually close this
out because our subDAG should be properly configured.
In here, we should be able to go in and now we can delete some of those code.
We don't need to write this create_trips_table or copy_trips task anymore.
Same with create_stations and copy_stations because we've parameterized or subDAGs above.
So, now we only have check_trips,
and check_stations, and our actual location_traffic_task.
So, you can see down here that we still have to
replace some of the usages of those create and copy_task.
We're going to jump back up above and we're going to look at our SubDagOperator.
So, we've instantiated the SubDagOperator,
we've provided the subDAG function call,
and we've properly parameterized
the subDAG with all of the arguments that it would need to get going.
So, we have a trip_subdag_task and we have a stations_subdag_task.
So, at the bottom here,
we're going to have a trip_subdag_task run before we actually
run our location_traffic_task, excuse me,
before we run our check_traffic_task or check_trips_task,
and then we're going to run our stations_subdag_task
before we run our check_stations_task.
At this point, the create and copy steps can be removed.
We can also remove the copy to check_stations dependencies.
Now, we have a properly configured DAG.
Let's see if Airflow loads the code.
So, it looks like I miss to find something here.
You can tell that if you've broken a DAG or your code isn't properly configured,
Airflow will actually pop up a warning saying,
"Hey, I couldn't parse your code."
So, here it's saying the check_trips_task could not be found so it wasn't defined.
So, let's see if we can see what's going on here.
So, the first thing we notice is that,
here, we have check_trips_task, right?
I've used that variable name.
But on line 55, it's actually defined as check_trips;
same thing with check_stations.
So, neither one of these variables is defined.
So, I'm going to go to line 79, going to delete off the task,
and so now we have properly named variables.
Let's go and reload Airflow and see if it has picked up or changes.
Now, when a DAG breaks,
when you've made a mistake, it can take Airflow a few moments to pick up your changes.
So, we're going to be patient and just give it a few moments here to pick up our changes.
You can see when it fails to load,
that Airflow actually, basically,
black out the names,
so you can't click on it, and it'll put
those little information bubble here that you can hover over saying,
"Hey, the DAG isn't available."
So, we can now see that our error is gone,
and we can see that lesson3.demo3 is now available again.
Airflow is now able to correctly parse our DAG.
So, we're going to look at the code.
We're just going to verify that everything looks correct.
We have our SubDagOperators, stations and trips.
We have our two checks,
a location_traffic_task, and we've reordered to use our subdag_task.
So, let's go ahead and actually run this code.
We go back to this menu, return on lesson3.demo3,
going to click Play, and then we're going to open up a DAG and see that it works.
So first, we're going to jump into our Graph View.
So, you'll notice this looks a little different.
We have a trips_subdag and the stations_subdag,
and we'll see we don't get a lot of information.
If I wanted to see more information,
I could click on the trips_subdag and click Zoom into Sub DAG.
This will show me more information.
I'm going to wait for this to execute so we can get a little farther along.
So, we can see this DAGs,
these two subDAGs are both running now and they both completed.
So, the two checks will know happen,
and then the calculate_location_traffic task will happen.
While they're doing that, let's take a look at our subDAG.
So, before we jump in in the black menu here,
you can see the operator type is SubDagOperator.
If I click on this and then I go to Zoom into Sub DAG,
I can actually see the steps that are part of my subDAG.
So, notice up here, our menu looks a little different.
SUBDAG: lesson3.demo3.trips_subdag.
We can see that here we can actually see
the PostgresOperators and the S3ToRedshiftOperator.
Likewise, in the graph,
we can see just the two tasks that are involved in our subDAG.
I can even click in and see the logs just like I could in the past.
So, let's return to their home menu,
we'll go back to lesson3.demo3,
and you can see there our DAG has now completed successfully.