Now that you've had a chance to try out exercise three,
let's walk through the solution.
So, first, we're going to go over to the code and have a look.
So, again, lesson3.exercise3, let's open up the DAG first.
You can see here, we have a subdag operator defined for
trips and a station subdag defined for stations,
and if we keep scrolling down,
you're going to see the only task left that's not
a subdag is the PostgresOperator for calculating location_traffic.
You can see our task ordering is that the trips_
subdag runs, then the location_traffic_task.
Same thing with stations_subdag.
We open up our subdag,
you can see if we come in here that we have the create and
copy tasks that you saw me move in during demonstration,
we now also have the check_task defined.
We made the check_task generic.
We use Python 3.0 formatting strings to say check,
and then rendered in the table name data.
We also made sure to pass on the DAG that we defined here in the subdag,
a redshift_conn_id and a table.
Once we did that, we made sure that after we ran
the copy_task that we ran the check_task.
So again, we called in our subdag here in our DAG.
Once we did that, we can go into the Airflow UI and we just want to make sure first,
we're going to turn this on.
We can come into the Airflow UI, look at lesson3.exercise3.
We want to make sure that the Graph View looks correct.
So we can see here, we have trips_subdag and
stations_subdag feeding into calculate_location_traffic.
So this is what you should see if your DAG was properly configured.
Now, we're going to go ahead and run this DAG once to see it execute.
So we're going to scroll back to the front page,
go to lesson3.exercise3, and click the "Play" button.
So, Airflow is going to start running lesson3.exercise3 in a moment here.
We're going to the Graph View and watch it progress.
So, the trips_subdag and the stations_subdag are now underway.
We'll wait just a few minutes for these to run.
It's worth noting while we're waiting for this to run,
that the coloring of these tasks actually indicates to us what kind of task they are.
So here, the Postgres operator is a light gray.
The subdag operator is a dark gray.
So, we can visually distinguish that something
is a subdag versus a normal DAG based on the color.
So now, both of our subdags have completed the trips_subdag and the station_subdag.
We can see this one took about 27 seconds as did this one.
Our calculate_location_traffic task is completed.
Again, if we wanted to make sure that there are subdags worked properly.
We can click on the "subdag" in the Graph View click "Zoom into Sub DAG".
Then, once we're in the subdag,
we can see that the subdag itself ran how long each of the task took,
and if we go to the Graph View,
you can see the components of our subdag.
So first, we create the table,
we load the trips data from S3 to Redshift and then we check the trips data.
Now, if we return to our subdag code,
you'll notice that this matches the task ordering that we defined.