As we all know, software can fail.
We've worked hard in this course to learn best practices
and construct resilient data pipelines in airflow.
Even with all that effort, at some point,
we'll encounter a bug and need to fix a problem in our production data pipelines.
With proper monitoring, we can be aware of
these issues as soon as they occur and act to fix them.
In this section, we'll learn about airflows monitoring features,
and how you can use them to stay ahead of pipeline problems.
Airflow DAGs optionally specify an SLA or service level agreement.
We mentioned this a couple times in the class.
But it's also worth noting that this can be defined as a task parameter,
time by which your task must complete.
For time sensitive applications,
these features are critical for developing trust amongst your pipeline customers,
and ensuring that data is delivered while still meaningful.
Slipping SLAs can also be early indicators of
performance problems or need to scale the size of your airflow cluster.
Here, I've taken a screenshot of the airflow UI.
You can see that I clicked on Browse,
and then I clicked on SLA misses to get us to this page.
So, in this example,
I set a couple of SLAs on lesson three,
exercise one, just to demonstrate what a missed SLA looks like.
So, if you're administrating an airflow data pipeline and you set an SLA on your tasks,
and your test started to miss their SLAs,
you can go to Browse,
SLA misses and see which of the tasks of your DAGs are starting to miss their timelines.
This is incredibly useful if you want to stay ahead of data getting out of date.
Airflow can be configured to send emails on DAG and task state changes.
These state changes may include successes, failures, or retries.
Failure emails can allow you to easily trigger alerts.
It's common for alerting systems like PagerDuty to accept emails as a source of alerts.
If a mission critical data pipeline fails,
one that your business relies on,
you will need to know as soon as possible to get online and get it fixed.
Airflow also comes out of the box with the ability to send
system metrics using a metrics aggregator called Statsd.
Statsd can be coupled with metrics visualization tools like Grafana,
to provide you and your team high-level insights into
the overall performance of your DAGs, jobs, and tasks.
You can check the classroom notes to learn more about Statsd and Grafana,
and how to get airflow to work with those two tools.
You can watch these metrics over time to see if
your airflow installation is growing slow or has gone offline.
These systems can be integrated into your alerting system such as PagerDuty,
so that you can ensure problems are dealt with immediately.
Most importantly, airflow system level metrics allow you and your team to
stay ahead of issues before they even occur by watching long-term trends.
So, in this example,
you can see the number of tasks successes for
our entire airflow installation from a given period of time.
So you can see the number of successes changing on the y-axis,
and the time progressing on the x-axis.
This visualization that you're seeing was taken as a screenshot out of Grafana,
driven by the stats from Statsd.