In this demonstration, we're going to walk through
how to define and use your own operators.
So, we're going to be doing lesson 3 demo 1.
So, the first thing I'm going do is,
open up lesson3 demo1.
In this demonstration, we're going to
replace some of our existing code with new custom operators.
So, you can see here on line 75,
we now have an S3ToRedshiftOperator.
I'm going to show you how we define an operator.
So first, I'm actually going to exit out of the dags folder.
So, we're in dags lesson 3 demo 1.
I'm going to close this up, and we're going to
look at a new folder that we haven't used yet in this class,
and that folder is the plugins folder.
This is where we're going to define our custom plugins.
So, now we've opened the plugins folder,
we're going to open another folder inside of this,
which is our operators folder.
This is where we placed our custom operators.
We're going to start by looking at the HasRowsCustomOperator.
So, this is a freely fairly good example of a basic custom operator.
The code on line 21 to 28,
should look really familiar.
This is the same code that you wrote for the previous exercise in lesson two.
So that would be, lesson two, exercise four,
where we add a data quality checks to our DAG.
So, you can see here, what we've done is,
we've moved this code into an execute function.
We'll come back to this in just a moment.
At the top here, we've imported a base operator from the Airflow Models File.
All airflow operators, custom or not,
inherit from the base operator.
So, in this class, we have the HasRowsOperator, which we've defined.
We've also defined this init function.
We've added two explicit arguments here,
redshift connection ID and table.
These are the two arguments that we absolutely have to
have to run the execute function below.
You can see here that we instantiate
the base class or call it base class constructor and then,
we set the table and redshift connection ID attributes on our object.
Next, we defined our execute function.
Every operator has an execute function.
Airflow calls the execute function to
actually execute the operator when it's time for that task to run.
You can see in here, that we've made use of self.table,
which we set on line 17,
and we've gone through and actually use
the redshift connection ID which we defined on line 18.
So, that's really all there is to it.
We could go ahead and actually instrument our DAG with this updated custom operator,
which you'll actually do in the exercise here shortly.
Before we go back, I'm going to show you a second example.
This is our S3ToRedshiftOperator.
You can see there's a few more arguments to this.
And just on line seven,
you can see just like the HasRowsOperator,
we've inherited from the base operator.
We again, we have an init class,
and we've taken a number of arguments,
and we've set the attributes on our class,
and again we've defined an execute function.
You can see here that we've take a number of arguments. Excuse me.
You can see here that our execute function performs a number of tasks.
These tasks should look familiar to you.
Essentially, what you're seeing here is the same as what you saw in
previous steps when we did the S3ToRedshift copy operation.
We've just made the code a little more generic.
You can see on line 48 that we're actually
taking the S3 key and formatting it or templating it.
So, you can see up here on line eight,
that we've told airflow that we want
the S3 key parameter to be templatable. What does that mean?
So, if we go back down to line 23 in our init, excuse me,
line 25 in our are init,
you can see that we take an S3 key parameter for our operator.
By saying on line eight,
that the S3 key field is templatable,
airflow would be use air for, excuse me,
airflow will use context variables to render that template.
So, this is important. If you think back to lesson one and lesson
two when we used say the execution date,
the previous DES or the next DES,
those are examples of using template variables.
So, this tells airflow that it needs to actually
render out that key before it gets passed into your operator.
So, down here on line 48,
we're actually taking that key and we're passing in the context to render it.
Finally, rendering that the actual SQL and then running it against redshift.
So, those are the two custom operators that we discussed.
If you want to see the explicit instructions for setting up your own operator,
we're going to add a link to the airflow instructions in the classroom.
There are a number of steps involved.
But once you've done it a few times,
it really isn't so bad and it's a great way to share code with your colleagues.
One final thing before we jump back into our dag,
you can see the init file under plugins.
So, we went to plugins init.py.
You can see that we've got one more class defined here.
We've imported from the Airflow.Plugins_ manager the airflow plugin class.
We've defined our own,
Udacityplugin inheriting from that Airflowplugin.
There are two things that you need to do to define a custom plugin.
You must always give it a name.
This actually determines how you import the code.
So, we would say,
from airflow.operators.Udacity plugin, import HasRowsOperator.
The next thing we've done is actually told airflow,
what operators we've created.
So, we created two operators,
HasRowsOperator and the S3ToRedshiftOperator.
So now, airflow will register and recognize both of these custom operators.
That under our belt, we're going to return to the dags folder,
go to lesson 3 demo 1,
and we're going to actually use the two of our S3ToRedshiftOperators.
So because these functions have been replaced with the custom operator,
we can actually go ahead and delete them.
But we'll wait just a moment to do that.
On line 75, you can see,
I've actually replaced our copy trips task with the S3ToRedshift Operator.
We've passed in, named parameters to actually get our S3ToRedshiftOperator configured.
So, instead of passing in a dictionary of arguments that we have to get out of context,
we can actually use name parameters.
So here, we're going to replace this with the trips table,
our redshiftconnection ID is redshift,
and our AWS credentials ID is AWS credentials.
One more thing I want to point out here,
we talked a little bit about template fields and our S3ToRedshiftOperator.
You can see us using templating here.
Execution date.year and execution date.Month.
Next, we'll take a look at our stations table.
So here, you can see again,
we're using the S3To Redshift Operator.
We're going to replace this table with the station's table,
the redshift connection ID and
the redshift and the AWS credentials id with AWS credentials.
You can see that we passed in the bucket name and the S3 key.
Now, since we've defined these with custom operators,
we can actually delete this code.
So, we have our task ordering is exactly the same as the past.
You can see, we still have our create and then copy task.
And with that completed, we're actually ready to go ahead and run our dag.
So, we're going to go ahead and refresh,
then we'll go to lesson3.demo1, verify the code.
So, you can see here, we've imported
HasRows Operator and we've imported S3ToRedshiftOperator.
We've removed those duplicated functions.
And we have our S3ToRedshift Operator defined here and here.
With that done, let's turn on our DAG and watch it run.
This DAG still has a monthly schedule.
So, we'll give this just a minute to run.
So,we can see, we already have a success on the creation on a table.
We're back to our graph view.
Now, we're loading the data from s3_ to_ redshift.
So, this is where we're actually using
our custom operator and you can see, when I hover here,
in this black box,
you can see Operator s3_ to_ redshift operator.
So, we'll give this just a moment to run.
All right. So, we've finished our load of stations data from S3ToRedshift.
We'll see if our trips data's completed yet.
So, our loading of trip from s3_ to_ redshift was completed.
A load of our trips is complete.
Great. So, now we've completed our execution of lesson3.demo1.