All right, welcome back guys.
So we're going to take a quick look at the solution to this.
We saw lesson one,
or lesson three demo one.
Now let's take a look at lesson three solution one.
So I'm going to go ahead and turn this on. We'll jump in here.
And you can see that our DAG looks very similar to before.
You'll notice the first difference at the top here though.
We have a PostgresOperator and an S3ToRedshiftOperator.
Now, you'll also see that we have a HasRowsOperator.
In our graph view, everything looks the same as it
did before but you'll notice if you hover over
the check_stations_data you'll see that the operator type is now HasRowsOperator.
Likewise, if we look at the code the function should be gone.
We no longer need the actual Python check code in this DAG definition.
And if we scroll down,
we're now using HasRowsOperator for
check_trips and we're using HasRowsOperator for check_ stations.
You can see at the bottom of the task ordering hasn't changed.
If you go back to our run,
we can now see that everything is completed successfully using our custom operators.