Once you start to build your own DAGs in Airflow,
you may begin to wonder what the right boundaries are between tasks.
In our bike share example,
tasks within the DAG have been defined for you.
Have you stopped to wonder why we have two S3 to Redshift load operations?
Why do we have two data quality checks instead of just one?
Why not just do them together?
Though it may seem obvious with the DAG sketched out in front of you,
in practice, finding these boundaries can be harder than you might think.
In this section, we'll cover some good rules to
use when reasoning about how to break apart tasks.
Every task in your DAG should perform only one job.
To paraphrase Ken Thompson's Unix philosophy,
write programs that do one thing, and do it well.
We can apply the same concept in writing the task within
our DAGs: Write tasks that do one thing, and do it well.
This is useful for you as a developer as you build your data pipelines.
If you revisit a pipeline you wrote six months ago,
you'll have a much easier time understanding how it works in
the lineage of the data if the boundaries between tasks are clear and well defined.
This is true in the code itself and with an Airflow UI.
So, you can see here,
we have just a single task.
It's pretty descriptive as to what it's doing: copying data from S3 to Redshift,
and it gives us a pretty clear idea of
exactly the operations that are happening within the task.
If we did three or four other things here,
this wouldn't make as much sense and it wouldn't be obvious what it was doing.
Tasks that do just one thing are often more easily parallelized.
This parallelization can offer a significant speedup in the execution of our DAGs.
We've already observed this effect in our bike share DAG.
You can see these two tasks are running at the same time.
You may have noticed that in the final exercise of Lesson
two that multiple copy and data quality checks could run at once.
This is because there are not cross-dependencies between these data sets.
If we had additional data sets,
we could add more copies and data quality checks.
In Airflow, we parallelize those copies and data quality checks as well.
One other thing I just want to emphasize here in this diagram,
so if this is our load trips and load stations task, when properly parallelized,
if we have time equals zero,
so this is zero seconds,
this is six seconds,
and this is 10 seconds,
Airflow will run both of these things at the same time.
So, the total duration will be whatever the longest running task is.
So, in this case,
load stations took six seconds,
load trips took 10 seconds.
So, the total execution for both of them will be about 10 seconds.
If instead we bundle all of our data loading and quality checks into just a few tasks,
it could take much longer to run our DAG.
So, if for whatever reason we decided to put these two tasks together into a single task,
then we would get the worst of both worlds.
Not only would we lose visibility,
we would also see that the execution time would go up.
So, again, if this is zero seconds and this is 16 seconds,
we know from our previous slide that load trips takes about 10 seconds.
If I had load stations running the same task after that and it took six seconds,
we would have a total of 16 seconds of execution time.
When a task fails,
it's important to quickly identify the issue and resolve the problem.
When each task in your DAG performs a single purpose,
it's easy to look at the Airflow UI to determine what exactly failed.
However, if your tasks are performing more than one task each,
you'll often struggle to figure out what broke.
Again, if in our bike share example we had loaded
both the trips and stations data at the same time in a single task,
how do we know which data set had failed to load if that task failed?
Was it the trips data set?
Was it the stations data set?
Maybe both of them failed to load. It's not clear.
Well-defined boundaries make our tasks more maintainable and easy to debug.
You can see in this example here that
Airflow uses the dark red to indicate that a task has failed.
The dark yellow means that an upstream task that
this task depends on has failed and this task can no longer run.
So, load trips from S3 to Redshift depends on the create trips table.
So, if the create trips table has failed,
then we can't run this task.