In this demonstration, we're going to look at a DAG that has
a single task with poorly defined boundaries.
We're going to see how we might refactor it into a cleaner,
simpler to understand series of tasks.
So, first, we're going to turn off lesson3.solution1.
We're going to return to the DAG's menu,
and then we're going to open up our demo2.
So, in demo2, we have one giant function.
We have this load_and_analyze function,
which you can see is grabbing our redshift connection,
running some code against redshift,
getting some records from redshift and checking to see what the oldest rider is,
then creating another table in redshift,
and then again checking to see who the youngest rider was.
Then there are even more SQL statements down here.
One is for lifetime_rides.
One is for city_station_counts.
Again, just to reiterate,
this is one function.
We have a single load_and_analyze function here.
So, in this DAG, we have DAG defined here.
We have this load_and_analyze function.
What would happen if something failed?
How would we know what failed and why?
If I were to have run this task, and we got, say,
to this lifetime_rides SQL statement,
and it failed, it wouldn't be immediately
obvious that that was the reason that the DAG had failed.
I'd have to actually open up the logs and read the logs to figure out what was going on.
So, a better way of doing this would be to actually create
PythonOperators and PostgresOperators for each one of these tasks.
So, I'm going to go ahead and get started with this,
and then I'm going to ask you to pick up where I left off to finish the refactor.
So, we'll start by looking at all the separate pieces of functionality in here.
So, we know that our SQL statements can be run
independently from the actual analysis function that we're running.
So, here, we have a redshift_hook that's running a CREATE TABLE.
This could be its own task.
After that task is completed,
then we could actually go ahead and get the records and perform some analysis,
figuring out who the oldest rider was.
So, let's go ahead and give that a shot.
So, I'm going to start by taking this code,
just taking the SQL code,
and copy it to the bottom.
I'm going to make an oldest_rider_ table task.
We're going to give it a task_id, we'll call it oldest_riders_table,
we're going to assign it a DAG,
and we're going to give it a SQL statement.
Then, of course, we also need to tell it postgres_connection_id. All right.
With that, we should be all set to go to actually remove
this from our load_and_analyze task.
So, I'm going to remove this code.
Next, we have this analysis function here,
where we're actually trying to get the birth year of
the oldest rider and then log it out.
So, we're going to make a new function to do that.
So, we're going to say we're going to write an oldest_rider function,
and we're actually just going to copy this code and paste it in here.
So, now we have an oldest writer function.
We've got our redshift_hook.
We're actually selecting the birth year from the oldest_riders.
We're taking those records,
and then we're logging the oldest rider.
So, I'm going to define the new PythonOperator here,
going to give it a task_id, going to assign it a DAG,
I'm going to give it a python_callable,
and I need to check what I named that function.
On line 12, we call it oldest_rider.
So, we'll go to the bottom of our code again,
and then I think that's everything.
We don't need to give it context because we didn't use context.
Let's double-check that real quick.
So, let's take a look.
Did we use context here?
It doesn't look like we did.
So, we don't need to provide context to this function.
If we were to provide context,
we would need to give this args and kwargs.
So, now that we've done that,
we can actually go ahead and delete this code that's been refactored into its own task.
So, one of the things that's really nice about this is now
load_and_analyze can run independently of oldest_riders_table,
and the oldest_riders_table needs to run before we print the oldest_rider.
So, we've gone ahead and save this file.
We've defined task ordering of our two new operators.
Then we're going to go in here, and we're going to
double-check that the code was picked up correctly.
So, you can see we have a log_oldest function here.
Excuse me, I pulled up the solution.
Didn't want to pull that up yet.
So, we're going to come to the main DAG menu.
We're going to look at lesson3.demo2.
We're going to look at the code.
You can see that we have an oldest_rider function.
You can see the code that we define is deleted.
We now only have the younger_riders code,
which you'll work on in your solution.
Then at the bottom here, we have
our older_riders_table task and our print_oldest_rider task,
and those two things line up.
So, we're going to go ahead and give this a shot.
Go back to DAGs,
and we're going to turn on lesson3.demo2.
Now, I didn't assign this a schedule.
So, you need to go ahead and click the Run button.
So, we're going to go back to lesson3.demo2,
and we're going to watch the progression.
All right. So, you can see load_and_analyze is actually running independently,
and this was the big bloated function that we're refactoring,
is running independently from the two tasks that we defined.
Already you can see that we have much, much improved visibility.
We have a better idea of what's happening instead of just this one giant function.
So, our older_riders_table has been created.
So, our PostgresOperator that we created is now complete,
and you can see it completed before the load_and_analyze function completed.
So, you've already seen the benefits of parallelization,
and then we printed the oldest_rider as well.
So, now that's completed.
Again, these two functions were able to
complete while other work was happening in load_and_analyze.
So, let's go see how old our oldest rider was,
and our oldest rider was apparently born in 1900.