So, the solution for exercise two
can be a little different depending upon exactly how you decided to break it apart.
You may have decided to make multiple DAGs,
or you may have decided just to create tasks within that DAG.
In my solution, I actually just created one dag,
so I didn't add an additional DAG,
and it created multiple tasks from our old giant single task.
So, you can see here we have our DAG,
we have the log oldest function which we created in the demonstration,
I've also created a log youngest task here,
or a log youngest function for us to call from a Python operator.
Below, we have our create_oldest_ task and our log_oldest_task which you already saw.
Likewise, we have a create_youngest_task and log_youngest_task,
which are nearly identical to the create_oldest and
log_oldest_tasks, but operate independently.
Finally, we have our lifetime rides task which creates a table,
and we have our city station count task which also creates a city station counts table.
At the very bottom, we have our ordering defined.
So we say that create_oldest_task must run before log_oldest_task,
and create_youngest_task must run before the log_youngest_task.
You'll notice that the lifetime_rides_task and
city_stations_task do not appear in the ordering of our DAG.
The reason for that is they're independent from the create_oldest and youngest_tasks.
So if we scroll to the top and go to the graph view,
we can see that those two tasks can run
independently of create_oldest and create_youngest.
Let's go back to the DAG view and we're going to trigger a run of this solution.
Actually first, I need to turn the DAG on,
so DAG is now on,
and I'm going to trigger a run of solution two.
Now, we'll open that back up,
and you can see that we've got a run scheduled, so it's executing.
Go to the graph view,
and you already notice how much faster
this is running then the first time we ran this when we had just a single task.
Lifetime_rides and city_station_count are already complete,
create_youngest and create_oldest are running.
Now, they're completed and we're going to log the oldest and youngest.
So, in the time it took to really just run a couple of tasks in this,
we were able to get through all six of our tasks.
So, not only do we have a speed advantage from doing this,
but the visibility of our DAG is much much better.