Commonly repeated series of tasks within DAGs can be captured as reusable subDAGs.
A subDAG is similar to a normal DAG,
except that it's created by a factory function that
parameterizes and returns the DAG configuration.
SubDAGs are always used as a piece of another DAG.
They do not stand on their own.
Let's revisit our bike share DAG for an example of where we can make use of a subDAG.
As we continue to add DAGs to Airflow,
we'll find functional overlap between our pipelines.
In this example, let's pretend that we wanted to try and correlate
weather patterns in our service area with any bike repairs that occurred.
To do that, we'll add another DAG to perform that analysis.
On the left here, you see the DAG that we've been working on through much of this class.
We have trips data and stations data going from S3ToRedshift.
We're checking that the data is high-quality, they HasRowsOperator.
Then, finally, we're using the PostgresOperator to execute station traffic analysis.
So, in the example I just mentioned,
we want to correlate repairs and weather data,
so we're going to load that data from S3ToRedshift.
Now, we're going to check to see if there are rows, and finally,
we are going to run our actual weather repair analysis using the PostgresOperator.
We may have a hunch that repairs go up when the weather is bad,
and repairs go down when the weather is good.
To prove that out, we'll build a DAG that
loads repairs and weather data from S3ToRedshift.
Then, we'll verify that data is present in our Redshift tables.
Finally, we'll perform our weather repair analysis.
Here's what our DAGs would look like if we replaced
our repeated S3ToRedshift copy operations with
the subDAG that was parameterizable and performed the same work.
So, see here, we have S3ToRedshift subDAG.
We've parameterized it with stations trips and repairs weather.
As you can see, it's much simpler to reason about
the high level goals of each one of these DAGs than it was in the previous slide.
It's important to notice that the specific details each one of
these DAGs is now harder to into it as well.
Replacing those related operations with a subDAG allows us to
decrease the amount of code we need to write and to maintain to create a new DAG.
There are additional benefits to subDAGs as well.
If we use a subDAG to perform common operation,
that means that bug fixes speedups and other enhancements can be made much more quickly.
That's because the code that you see here is actually shared between these two subDAGs.
It also means that those same changes can be distributed to
all DAGs that use the subDAG as soon as the update occurs.