You guys already saw the solution to this but real quick,
I'm going to walk through one more time what we did.
So we had these four functions defined.
Your functions are slightly different to mine.
But then, we defined three Python operators,
and these three operators are for
all intents and purposes the same as our Hello World task,
but we gave them different IDs and different Python callables.
Then, down here, we configured our DAG
using the task dependency ordering operations down here.
So they just needed these double [inaudible].
So we said Hello World task comes before Current Time task and Working Directory task.
Then, when Current Time task and Working Directory task are complete,
we can run the complete task.
Then, the output that we saw in the UI is very similar to this.
We have these four tasks that are complete,
and we can go to Tree View and see a history of our runs.