So data pipelines interact with data originating from and going to many systems.
Because of this, most Airflow DAGs have to interact
with connection data and variables that may change often.
Thankfully, Airflow provides a system to
modify and update this data without ever having to change your code.
We'll review connection and variables in detail in Lesson 3.
Once you've configured your connections in the Airflow UI,
you can configure Airflow Hooks to use
these credentials to interact with your data stores and
other external systems such as databases like Redshift, Postgres, and MySQL.
One of the major benefits of this is that you don't have to worry about
how and where to store these connection strings and secrets in your code.
Your code just needs to know the name of the connection.
Here's an example of what this might look like.
You can see here we've imported a PostgresHook from Airflow Hooks PostgresHook,
and we've instantiated it by giving it the name demo.
So this is a string,
and you'll see in just a moment here where we do the demonstration
how to actually name your connections when you create them.
But let's just presume that we've created a connection called demo,
we're going to instantiate the PostgresHook,
and then every hook and Airflow has a number of functions
defined on it so that we can automatically get some usage out of it.
So in this particular case,
we're saying get me a Pandas DataFrame.
So Airflow will go off and run the SQL statement SELECT all FROM rides,
and then the result will be loaded into
a Pandas DataFrame and then returned back to Airflow.
Just how Airflow offers a number of operators out of the box,
Airflow ships with dozens of hooks.
Chances are Airflow already has a hook
defined for the system you'll want to integrate with.
So you can see here a couple of interesting ones.
We already talked about PostgresHook, which by the way,
we're going to use PostgresHook to interact with Redshift for the rest of this course.
Postgres and Redshift use the same underlying systems for topic for communication.
SlackHook if you want to send messages to a Slack channel,
HttpHook for interacting with HTTP APIs,
and so on and so forth.