Now, that we're familiar with data pipelines,
let's spend some time learning about data validation.
Data validation is the process of ensuring that data is present, correct, and meaningful.
Validating that data that passes through our data pipelines
helps ensure that our pipelines are producing correct results.
Data validation can be done manually by quality assurance,
data engineers, or even your data customers.
However, with that being said,
it's much preferable to perform data validation in an automated fashion.
Validation can and should become part of your pipeline definitions.
There are previously bikes for example,
we loaded data from S3 to Redshift.
We transformed it, and then we ranked locations by how busy they are.
What would happen if our system miscalculate the location ranking?
What if no data was produced at all?
When we make mistakes in our data pipelines,
they can lead to some serious problems for our businesses,
for our customers, and for people who depend on that kind of data.
So, it's really important that we perform this step of
data validation to ensure that the data we're creating is accurate and correct.
Before the data engineer moves on from the extract load step to any transformations,
they would likely assert that Redshift contains
the same number of rows in Redshift as were extracted from S3.
After that first validation step is passed,
the data pipeline processes the data in Redshift and
creates a fact table based on the raw input data.
At this point, validity assertion can be made about the data itself,
through the numbers produce why an unexpected range with any output data produced at all.
The day-to-day work of most data engineers is centered around
the movement and transformation of data in some form.
Data pipelines give us a set of logical guidelines and a common set of
terminology to work with when we're describing
the various tasks involved in this process.
With a solid understanding of what data pipelines are, how they work,
and how to validate their output,
you'll be well-equipped to start your journey as a data engineer.