Now let's move on to clustering columns.
Clustering columns- The PRIMARY KEY is made up of
either just the PARTITION KEY or with the addition of CLUSTERING COLUMNS.
The CLUSTERING COLUMNS will determine the sort order within a Partition.
The clustering columns will sort the data in sorted descending order.
More than one clustering column can be added or like we talked about before, or none.
So, in this case,
we have a Composite key with it we're partitioning by year,
and then from there we have a clustering column on artist's name, and album name.
So, you can see here in this example if I did a select star from that music library,
you can see that I have my year,
and then my artist's name which is then in alphabetical order in descending order;
E comes before T,
and B comes before M. Then after that,
it's going to sort by album name.
So, here you can see again so,
Elvis so Blue Hawaii,
and then we're going to sort the Beatles.
Here we're going to have Rubber Soul,
and then here I just wanted to make sure it was something that came after Rubber Soul,
so I made it not really an album it's called, 'Showing the order'.
So, here it's going to be in descending order as you can see.
Then here we'll have the item for the Monkees.
From there, the clustering column will sort in sorted order,
and how they were added to the primary key.
So, for example, in this example that I just showed,
they will be distributed by the key,
then sorted in descending order by first the artist's name, and then the album name.
So, the primary key is made up of a partition key which in this case is year,
and a clustering column which is the artist's name.
Remember this is just an example.
It might not be unique enough of a value.
Let's say that the artist created two albums in one year.
Then this data model would not hold up.
But just for the sake of this demo,
we're going to assume that it's unique.
So, here we're going to clustering or excuse me,
our partition key here which is year,
and our clustering column artist's name.