All right. So, let's look at a demo,
let's focus on clustering columns.
In this demo, we're going to walk through the basics of
creating a table with a good primary key,
and clustering columns in Apache Cassandra,
inserting rows of data,
and doing a simple SQL query to validate the information.
For your package, connect your database,
connect your keyspace. All right.
Let's imagine we'd like to start creating a new music library of albums.
We've created a lot of music library albums tables in this lesson, so,
imagine there are other things that you can do
data modeling on other than music libraries,
but this is just what we're going to use to walk as through.
We want to ask one question of our data,
give me every album in my music library that was released by
an artist with album name in descending order and city in descending order.
So, my query might look something like this,
select star from music library or artist name equals the Beatles.
So, then here's my collection of data that I have.
So, how should we model this data?
What should be our primary key and our partition key?
Since our data is looking for the artist name, let's start with that.
From there, we'll need to add other elements to make sure that the key is unique.
Again, because we need to start with artist name,
we have duplicates, for example, for the Beatles,
we have three rows that have the Beatles as their artist's name.
So that's not going to be unique enough to be our soul partition key.
So we're going to need to add other elements to make sure that the key is unique.
We also need to add the city,
and the album name as clustering columns to sort the data.
That shouldn't be enough to make our row key unique.
So, we're going to have music library,
column year, artist name, album name, and city.
So again, we're going to start with our partition key,
our partition key always goes first,
artist name, from there we're going to have album name, and city.
Let's create the table if it does not exist.
Again, album name and city are our clustering columns.
Great, let's insert our data into the table.
Again this looks like all the other inserts that we've done before.
Let's validate our data model.
Did it work?
If we look for albums from the Beatles,
we should expect to see three rows.
Again here's our query,
select star from music library were artist's name equals the Beatles,
and we're going to run that query and print the result.
Awesome. The Beatles, Beatles For Sale London 1964,
The Beatles Let it Be Liverpool,
The Beatles Rubber Soul and Oxford.
So as you can see,
we have our partition key,
and then our clustering columns are in order.
Beatles, let, and rubber that's in descending order.
Success, it worked.
We created a unique primary key that evenly distributed our data,
with clustering columns that sorted our data,
and for the sake of the demo I will drop the table,
and finally am going to close my session.