So, now we're going to be talking about the WHERE clause.
We've been utilizing the WHERE clause
extensively through lesson one through lesson three.
But I really want to dive deep on how we're actually using it?
The best ways to use it et cetera.
Data modeling and Apache Cassandra is query focused.
The focus needs to be on the WHERE clause.
The partition key must be included in your query and
any clustering columns that can be used in the order they appear in your primary key.
Failure to include a WHERE clause will result in an error.
Let's walk through an example with our music library table.
Because we have quite a few queries on this screen here.
Let's walk through them one by one.
So, the first query here,
select star for music library where year equals 1965.
Will get you back everything in your partition.
This is all the data you have stored on one node.
Be careful with this type of query.
Remember, no sequel is made for big data.
This could be getting back terabytes of data or even more.
Always be aware of the potential performance issues that
might result from pulling back large amount of data.
Our second query here,
select star from music library where year equals
1965 and the artist's name equals The Beatles.
See here that we're utilizing our clustering column to fetch more specific data.
We must use the clustering columns in the order that they were
provided in the primary key.
I cannot do a select star from music library where year
equals 1965 and then album name Let It Be.
That will result in an error because we partitioned by
year and our clustering column was artist's name, not album name.
Number three our third query,
select star from music library where year equals
1965 and artist's name equals The Beatles and album name equals Rubber Soul.
In this case, we will be getting back one row of information in our table.
I have used my partition key and all my clustering columns to fetch the data.
So, here's an example of the WHERE clause,
select star from music library where year equals
1965 and artist's name equals The Beatles and album name equals Rubber Soul.
Then we get back to that one row that we discussed.
Select star from table.
The WHERE clause must be included in our executed query.
It is recommended that one partition be queried at a time for performance implications.
It is possible to do a select star from table without
the WHERE clause if you add a configuration called ALLOW FILTERING to your query.
This is risky but available and absolutely necessary.
They should be done with extreme caution.
I actually will not even provide the syntax for you but it is available to you.
No sequel is all about big data and high-performance.
Keep those factors in mind when performing queries.
Thousands of nodes systems exist of Apache Cassandra and select star on
that system will be trying to pull all the data to the client from thousands of nodes.
This is called a full table scan.
Best case, would that it'd be extremely slow.
Worst case, it could bring down your system.
Adding the WHERE clause we'll make sure this doesn't happen and
you're serving the requests with low latency and high performance.