All right. Demo four.
Let's focus more on this WHERE clause.
We're going to go and open our Jupyter notebook.
Lesson three, demo four,
and using the WHERE clause.
In this demo, we're going to walk through the basics
of using the WHERE clause in Apache Cassandra.
We're going to import our library,
connect to our cluster,
create our key space if it does not exists,
connect to our key space, and there we go.
Let's imagine we'd like to start creating a new music library of albums.
We want to ask four questions of our data.
Give me every album in my music library that was released in a given year.
Select star from music library where year equals blank.
Give me the album that is in my music library
that was released in a given year by The Beatles.
Select star from music library where year
equals a particular year that you choose and artist name.
In this case, we're choosing The Beatles.
Give me all the albums released in a given year, in a given location.
Select star for music library where year equals 1970 and location equals Liverpool.
Give me a city that the album Let It Be was recorded.
Select city from music library where year equals 1970,
and artist name The Beatles,
and album name Let It Be.
Here's a collection of our data,
similar to that data that we've seen before in other demos and exercises.
How should we model this data?
Again, every time I start these demos,
that's what I start you with because that's what we have to be thinking about.
How should I model this data knowing my queries in advance?
What should be our primary key and our partition key?
Since our data is looking for year, let's start with that.
From there, we'll add clustering columns on artist name and album name.
So, let's create our music library,
year, artist name, album name, and city.
We're going to partition by year.
We're going to use a clustering column for artist name and album name.
Let's insert our data into the table.
Again, very similar to what you've seen before.
Let's validate our data model with our four queries.
Select star from music library where year equals 1970.
So, I get 1970, The Beatles,
and 1970, The Carpenters.
Success, it worked.
Let's try our second query.
Select star from music library where year equals 1970.
I think I want to bring up a point here.
So, as we've been talking about one query per one table,
which is a wonderful way to do data modeling.
But at the same time,
you can only do one query per one table.
You can do more than one type of query.
But this case, we have both.
But in that case, you can do more than one type of
query like we're doing here with year equals
1970 and year is equal 1970 and artist name equals The Beatles. You can't do that.
But you're just adding more of
the clustering columns and making your results more specific.
So, it's a different query but it's still utilizing the same data model.
I hope that's clear. So, let's try that.
Select star from music library where year equals
1970 and the artist name equals The Beatles.
Awesome. I got back my result.
It worked. Let's try the third query.
Select star from music library where year equals 1970 and location equals Liverpool.
An error, a very ugly error at that.
Undefined column name location,
not very clear. But what does it mean?
Error. You can not try to access a column or
clustering columns if you have not used the other defined clustering columns.
Let's go back to where we created our table.
So, here, we have our partition key of year,
our clustering column of artist name,
and our clustering column of album name.
You have to utilize to do a query.
You have to use these in order.
Also, if we wanted to use and city,
we have to use it after we've used all of these columns.
So, year, artist name,
album name, and city.
We can't just use any column.
We have to use all the clustering columns in order.
That's why we got a failure.
That value is to be expected.
So, let's see if we can do this in a different way.
Select city from music library where year equals 1970,
and artist name equals The Beatles,
and album name Let It Be.
So, again, we're utilizing all of our clustering columns in the query,
and we get back Liverpool.
So, for the sake of the demo,
I will drop the tables.
I got an error there, how interesting.
That's because I didn't create,
I've already dropped music library one.
Yeah. Unconfigured table, music library one.
That's just a typo. I didn't need this.
Then, we'll close our connection. Awesome.