All right. So we're ready to wrap up.
We've gone through all our demos and all our exercises.
So what did we learn in this lesson?
We learned about the basics of distributed database design and why
the affects of that will affect our data modeling decisions.
NoSQL is already optimized for rights.
So we must model our data to allow reads to be fast.
We must have our queries and model the tables to our queries.
Always data model with queries in mind.
Importance of denormalization: We learned why
we must denormalize to allow for fast reads.
We learned about Apache Cassandra and how it is a very popular NoSQL database.
Then it's also used in a number of very high profile companies.
We learned about the primary key,
partition key, and clustering columns.
We learned about the primary key and how that is made up of partition key,
which distributes the data,
and the clustering column, which orders the data.
We learned about the where clause as we must think about our queries,
and that we have limitations on select star.