So let's wrap up our course.
What did we learn in lesson one, two and three?
In lesson one, we learned about the fundamentals of when to use
relational databases and when to use a non-relational database.
We learned about their strength and their weaknesses.
In lesson two, we learned about the fundamentals
of how to do relational database modeling.
We focused on normalization and moving data into third normal form.
We also learned about when to denormalize even in relational data modeling.
We learn when to use fact and dimension tables and how
those come together to create a star schema which is highly used in industry.
In lesson three, we learned about the importance of
denormalization for NoSQL database modeling.
We learned that tables must be denormalized as there are no joints in NoSQL databases.
We learned about the fundamentals of NoSQL database modeling that focus on queries first.
We discussed how to create the primary key
out of the partition key and clustering columns.
We talked about the basics of distributed database design to help us
understand why data modeling is different from NoSQL database modeling.
Remember, the critical thinking skills you employ when you do data modeling is
a skill that is and should be independent of the type of database you're working with.
Once you have these skills,
you'll be able to transfer these skills to any database you are working with.
The skill is universal,
but data models between systems should be carefully
reviewed before doing any kind of blind copy paste.
I've really enjoyed creating these lessons and
sharing my understanding of data modeling with you all.
Congrats on finishing this course and thank you.