So, let's just go through some terminology.
NoSQL and non-relational are interchangeable terms.
So, NoSQL equals not only SQL.
For the rest of this lesson,
I'll refer to non-relational databases as NoSQL databases.
Historically, this did stand for non-SQL or NoSQL.
But as we learned in lesson one,
NoSQL has come to mean not only SQL.
As languages like Cassandra query language closely mimics SQL and they're very close.
So, let's just do a quick refresher on when to use a NoSQL database.
So, if you need high availability,
you have large amounts of data.
You need linear scalability.
You need low latency,
you need fast reads and writes.
For example; if you are going to be using Apache Cassandra,
that's a good example of when you would use a NoSQL database is to use Apache Cassandra.
So, let's talk a little bit about what Apache Cassandra actually is.
So, it's an open source NoSQL database.
You can go download the code right now.
It's all open source and you can go download it, check it out.
Run it. Whatever you want do contribute to it. We would all love that.
It has a masterless architecture and it has high availability.
It's linearly scalable.
So, like I said Apache Cassandra is an open-source technology that was created
at Facebook and became a top-level Apache project in 2010.
It was created to handle
big data challenges that relational databases were failing to meet.
It's a masterless architecture with no single point of
failure which makes it highly available.
It has low latency for reads and writes and it's linear scalable.
You add more nodes to just a quick note on when I use the term nodes,
we use that a lot in the distributed database world.
But it's really a server.
It can mean server or VM or it's just a system.
One single entity of that system whatever that a Docker container,
whatever that system is that's what it means.
So, when we say nodes that's what we're referring to.
So, as you add more nodes to the system,
your performance will actually increase
linearly when you're thinking about linear scalability.
Apache Cassandra is used at the backend for some of those most popular apps.
Basically, if you take a look at your phone,
some of the apps that you use every day,
Apache Cassandra is the backend.
So, very popular apps that use Apache Cassandra are Uber,
Netflix, Hulu, and Twitter.
Those are just a few. Another example is Apple.
Apple has over a 7,000 node deployment of Apache Cassandra.
Companies like DataStax, Apple,
Twitter and Facebook are all major contributors to the project.
Remember with an open-source project,
anyone is free to contribute.