Let's talk of some of the basics of NoSQL database design.
So, before I get started I just kind of
want to let you know that the reason that we have to do a little
bit more on the distributed database design is because the difference in
the design is why our data modelling has to be different than relational databases.
So, I just want to focus on that.
That's why we're talking about some of
these design concepts that we didn't really touch in relational.
In a distributed database,
in order to have high availability you need copies of your data. Let's break that down.
First, what is a distributed database?
This is a database that has been scaled out horizontally.
It's not just a single system but a database made up of multiple machines.
Second, high availability.
This means that my system is always up and there's no downtime
or very little downtime but essentially no downtime.
That isn't to say that all my nodes are always up because nodes will fail.
It's just the nature of how this works.
If you have 7,000 machines running one of them is going to
fail and because the nodes will fail,
that node will go down.
Third, if my system is distributed and my nodes will go down,
this means I need copies of my data.
My data cannot just live in one place.
With the fact that my data is copied throughout my system leads to
the fact that my data may not be up to date in all locations.
This is called eventual consistency.
So, let's talk about what eventual consistency means.
A consistency model used in distributed computing to achieve high availability.
That informally guarantees that if no new updates are made to a given data item,
eventually all access to that item will return the last updated state.
This is basically saying that over time if
no new changes are made that each copy of my data will be the same.
But this also means that if there are new changes,
the value of my data I should say,
maybe different in different locations.
Now, many people hear that and are very concerned.
First and foremost we are talking about
milliseconds that the data may be in fact inconsistent.
Secondly, there are workarounds to prevent getting stale data that are outside
the scope of this course but rest assure they've been put in place to prevent issues.