The CAP Theorem. This is a theorem in computer science that
states it is impossible for distributed data store to
simultaneously provide more than two out of the three following guarantees: consistency,
availability, and partition tolerance.
Consistency. Every read from the database gets
the latest and correct piece of data or it gets an error.
Availability. Every request is received and a response
is given without a guarantee that the data is the latest update.
Partition Tolerance.
The system continues to work regardless of losing network connectivity between nodes.
When your system is running fine,
there's no network failures.
You can also have availability and consistency.
But when the system has network failures,
then you may only have consistency or availability.
Apache Cassandra and other NoSQL databases
choose to be highly available at the potential cost of consistency.
It is an AP (Availability and Partition tolerant) database.
Remember, this only comes up during network failures.
I want to make it clear that we're learning about
these concepts because the difference
in the design of NoSQL databases affects how we will model the data.