The Importance Of Denormalization in Apache Cassandra.
Denormalization of tables in Apache Cassandra is absolutely critical.
The biggest take-away when doing data modelling in Apache Cassandra is to
think about your queries first. I want to say that again.
Think about your queries first.
There are no joins in Apache Cassandra.
In relational data modeling,
what worked well for relational database cannot
be moved over as is into Apache Cassandra.
Normalized tables will need to go through the process of
denormalization to be able to fit into the Apache Cassandra data model.
What queries will be performed on that data?
This is what you'll need to know in advance.
This must be the number one priority
when doing data modelling in NoSQL or Apache Cassandra.
Again, if you're migrating some of your workloads from relational to a NoSQL database,
it cannot be transformed as is.
You're going to have to do some new data modelling task on
it to be able to get it transform into the correct data model.
If you walk away knowing that, you're in good shape.
So let's talk a little bit more about data modelling in Apache Cassandra.
So denormalization is not just okay, it's a must.
Normalization into third normal form will not work in Apache Cassandra.
There are no joins in Apache Cassandra.
Without joins, I can only query on one table at a time.
Denormalization must be done for fast reads.
Apache Cassandra has been optimized for fast writes.
Again, if we were talking more about the architecture of Apache Cassandra,
you'd be able to see that the right path is actually very beautiful in its simplicity.
But if you want fast write, pardon me.
If you want fast reads,
you must set yourself up for success with a good data model.
Nothing is magic and nothing comes for free.
So because of that you're going to have to set yourself up with a good data model.
Again, think queries first.
If you walk away knowing that, you're in good shape.
In relational data modeling,
we were concerned about slow writes with denormalized tables.
Since you'll have duplicates of your data and need to write
update and insert to more than one table for the same piece of data.
But because Apache Cassandra has been optimized for that,
there should be no concern.
Again, no joins.
One table per query is a great strategy.
This will lead to data replication.
You're going to have redundant data.
You're going to have extra copies of your data.
Basically, the exact opposite of what we're worried about in lesson two.
But the performance benefits and high availability of
the system far outweigh any additional storage costs.
Remember, storage is an expensive.
Losing customers to outages or low latency is not.
Let's take a look at this graphic here.
So here, we're talking about again,
a good comparison between Relational Databases and
NoSQL Databases or thinking about data
modelling and the fact that we no longer have joins.
So in this case in a relational database,
we can have our query represented here.
We can have one query that's accessing two tables,
three tables, as many tables as we want because we can join them together.
Now, in NoSQL databases, again,
one query per one table.
One query per one table.
You cannot join the data together.
You can only access one table at a time.
Just to reiterate the idea of no joins and using one query on one table.
This diagram compares the approach for
relational versus NoSQL databases like Apache Cassandra.
In relational databases, one query can access and join data from multiple tables.
In Apache Cassandra, the queries can pull data from a single table.
This is important to model with your data in mind.
So again, think two queries, two different tables.
So let's say I want to do two queries.
One is all albums in a given year and all albums by given artist.
So, here's just a quick example of what that would look like.
So in this case, I want to get all albums by particular year.
So I'm going to do a select star from music library,
where year equals and then I can fill in whatever year that I'm looking for.
Over here, I want to do a select star from album library where again,
a different table where the artist name equals the Beatles.
So in this case,
we have partitioned our data by year and in this case we've
partitioned our data artist's name. No don't be afraid.
You're seeing a lot of duplicate data between these two tables and that is okay.
If you're getting a little lost on when I said partitioning of the data,
we're going to talk about that a lot more here very soon.
So again, the data in these tables is going to be duplicated.
But that's okay in the nature of having denormalized tables.
What is important is that we have two queries that we're able to
execute against our data in a high-performance, no downtime system.