So just a quick word on CQL.
Cassandra Query Language is the way that we interact with the database.
It's very similar to SQL, except again,
no JOIN no GROUP BY and there's not any subqueries,
and they're not in CQL and they're not supported by CQL.
In prior years, authentic Cassandra tables were assessed using a protocol called Thrift.
But that was very difficult to use and
hard for users coming from the relational CQL world.
There are many language drivers,
majority supported by datastacks to integrate into an application.
You've seen in lesson one in our demos and the exercises,
we were we're utilizing the Python driver.
Other popular drivers are Java,
C sharp, NodeJS, etc.
There's many many out there,
and again, they're all open source.
So if you have an idea for a new one, submit the code.
Go for it, go develop it.
We'll continue to use the Python driver in the next set of demos and exercises.