So, the primary key is how each row can be uniquely
identified and how the data is distributed across the nodes or servers in our system.
The first element of the primary key is
the partition key which will determined the distribution.
The primary key is made up of
either just the partition key or with the addition of clustering columns.
Again, the primary key is made up of
The partition key will determine the distribution of data across the system.
The partition keys row value will be hashed,
turned into a number and stored on
the node in the system that holds that range of values.
I'm just letting you know that extra piece of information there.
Again, this goes more into the design and architecture of distributed databases.
So, if you're interested in this topic there's
much more information out there that you can access to learn about that.
Alright. So, here's an example of a primary key
using a simple primary key which is also our partition key.
So, I'm going to create table music library.
Again, your int is going to be int,
artist name is text and album name text and then our primary key will be then by year.
So again, that means our data will be distributed across our system by the year.
So, our primary key is also our partition key.
So, some key points about primary keys,
they must be unique.
A primary key must be unique to each row.
There are no duplicates in Apache Cassandra.
Think about your primary key,
is it going to end up resolving to a single?
Row. If you make your primary key first name,
only one Amanda will be allowed in your database,
but this is a very common name and there will be more than one.
Data will be overwritten if a new value comes in with the same primary key.
An error will not be thrown and the original data will be overwritten.
Hashing of this value results in placement on particular nodes in the system.
The value will be hashed to a numeric value
and the value will determine whether data will live on the system.
Either node one, node two or node 7,000.
Data distributed by this partition key.
The data will be distributed across the system by this key.
You want to pick a key that will evenly distribute the data as best you can.
For example, if you've distributed a customer table by state,
you're likely to see an uneven distribution
because more people live in California than Vermont.
Simple or composite.
The simple primary key is just one column that is also the partition key.
A composite primary key is made up of more than one column and will assist in creating
a unique value and will help you in getting your retrieval queries.
They have one or more clustering columns.
We'll talk more about clustering columns in the next section.
Again, here's our composite key.
So, now we're seeing that same type of query that we had before on
music library of the create table and in this case,
we have primary key and we have a composite key.
We're going to distribute by year with a combination of artist name.
So, both of these are the partition key,
these values will be hashed together.
You'll get one value back and then that data will be stored on a particular node.
All of this together is the primary key.