All right. So let's go on to our next demo which is going to
focus on utilizing and using our primary key.
I'm going to my Jupyter Notebook,
and I'm going to open lesson three,
demo two, all about the primary key.
So, let's focus on that.
By the way, this eye is the Cassandra logo if anybody was wondering.
In this demo, we're going to walk through the basics of creating a table,
with a good primary key in Apache Cassandra,
inserting rows of data,
and doing a simple SQL query to validate the information.
We're going to import our library,
we're going to connect to the database,
and we're going to create our key space if it doesn't already exist,
and we'll connect to that key space.
Let's Imagine we'd like to start creating a new music library of albums.
We're going to work through one of the queries from exercise one.
We want to ask one question of our data: Give me
every album in my music library that was released in a given year.
Select star from music_library,
where year equals 1970.
Here's the collection of our data.
Here's the year, we have information about the city,
we have artist's name and album name. So let's look at our data.
How should we model this data?
Let's think about it. What should be our primary key?
What should be our partition key?
Since our data is looking for the year, let's start with that.
Is partitioning our data by year a good idea?
In this case, our data is very small.
But if we had a large data set of albums partitioned by year,
it may be a fine choice.
You would need to validate from your data set,
look at your own data and then model it to that.
But, essentially, we want to spread the data equally across our nodes.
So, in this case, we're going to create a table called music_library with a column year,
artist's name, album name, and city,
and our primary key is going to be on year.
So let's create our table.
Let's insert our data into the table.
So we're going to insert all that data we saw up above in this chart.
So, let's insert into our table,
and let's validate our data model, Did it work?
In this case, we can use the year 1970 or we can use any year.
So I'm showcasing this here.
So we're going to look for albums that were released in 1965.
We should expect to see two rows.
So let's go back here to our chart.
As you can see, there is The Beatles and Rubber Soul, 1965.
We also have The Who,
My Generation also 1965.
So I should expect to see those two back when I run this query.
That didn't work out. Why is that?
Because we did not create a unique primary key. That's why.
So, I had written in that 1965 for The Beatles,
and then it got overwritten by The Who,
My Generation. So let's try again.
Let's focus on making the primary key unique.
Look at our data set.
Do we have anything that is unique for each row?
We have a couple of options.
In this case, we have city and album name,
but that will not give us the query we need,
which we are looking for the album in a particular year.
Let's make a composite key of the year and the album name.
This is assuming that the album name is unique to that year.
Pardon me. That is assuming that the album name is unique to the year it was released.
This is not a bad bet.
But, remember, this is just a demo.
You will need to fully understand your own data set.
No betting on your own data.
So, we're going to create the table,
and again we're going to use a composite key here with year and album name.
We're going to create that query,
and again we're going to do our insert.
So, let's validate our data model. Did it work?
If we look for albums from 1965,
now we should see two rows.
Awesome, success. It worked.
We created a unique primary key that evenly distributed our data.
For the sake of the demo, I will drop the tables,
and we're going to close our connection.